我们来到AFA物业会见孩子的父亲。
We came to the AFA property to meet the child's father.
Vinimos al predio de AFA para encontrarnos con el padre de la criatura.
他们称她为母马。
They call her the mare.
Le dicen la yegua.
我们刚刚在 Clank Lionel Scaloni 中得知了这样一个绰号。
and we just learned of such a nickname in Clank Lionel Scaloni.
y nos acabamos de enterar de semejante apodo en Clank Lionel Scaloni.
欢迎，莱昂内尔·斯卡罗尼 (Lionel Scaloni)，很高兴您在 AFA Paraclan 项目的家中欢迎我们。
Welcome, Lionel Scaloni, a pleasure that you have welcomed us here in your home, in the AFA Paraclan project.
Bienvenido, Lionel Scaloni, un placer que nos hayas recibido acá en tu casa, en el proyecto de AFA Paraclan.
一切进展如何？
How is everything going?
¿Cómo va todo?
嗯，谢谢。
Well, thank you.
Bueno, gracias.
我很荣幸收到邀请，希望大家享受一切。
The honor is mine for the invitation and I hope people enjoy everything well.
El honor es mío por la invitación y espero que la gente disfrute todo bien.
10 年前，即 2014 年，你在亚特兰大踢职业生涯的最后一个赛季。
10 years ago, 2014, you were playing your last season as a professional at Atalanta.
Hace 10 años, 2014, jugabas tu última temporada como profesional en Atalanta.
你用了五个吗？
Did you use five?
¿Usabas la cinco?
你玩得不多。
You didn't play much.
No jugaste mucho.
在你的职业生涯和生活的那个阶段你在想什么？
What were you thinking about at that point in your career and your life?
¿En qué estabas pensando ya a esa altura de tu carril y de tu vida?
这是我的最后一年。
This is my last year.
Este es mi último año.
你已经有点专注于将要发生的事情了。
You were already kind of focusing on what was going to happen.
Ya estabas como enfocándote en lo que iba a pasar.
是的，不仅是在 2014 年，也就是我受过重伤的几年前。
Yes, not only in 2014, years before I had a significant injury to it.
Sí, no sólo en el 2014, ya años antes yo tuve una lesión importante en el.
2005年，世界杯之前...
In 2005, before the World Cup...
en el 2005, antes del mundial de...
作为一名来自德国的球员，我的腿筋严重脱离，我的职业生涯开始放缓。
from Germany as a player, I had a pretty strong hamstring detachment and my career started to slow down a bit.
de Alemania como jugador, tuve una desinserción bastante fuerte del isquiotibial y ya mi carrera un poco empezó a
走另一条路，我已经开始考虑......
to go the other way and I already started thinking about...
a ir para otro lado y ya empecé a pensar en...
成为一名教练，尽管我已经有了这个想法。
in being a coach, although I already had it in mind.
en ser entrenador, aunque ya lo tenía en la cabeza.
每当你坚持要当教练的时候。
Whenever you insist on being a coach.
Siempre que insistes en ser entrenador.
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
是的，是的，我总是一个善于提问、善于倾听的人。
Yes, yes, I was always one to ask, to listen.
Sí, sí, siempre fui de preguntar, de escuchar.
出于好奇，2011 年我在罗马拉齐奥学习了第一门课程。
to be curious and in 2011 I took the first course while at Lazio in Rome.
de ser curioso y en el 2011 hice el primer curso estando en la Lazio en Roma.
我首先参加了欧足联课程，然后...
I did the UEFA course the first and...
Hice el curso UEFA el primero y...
我已经看到足球即将结束，我老了，我的身体不再那么好，我很难踢球。
And I already saw that football was ending, I was old, I was no longer so well physically, it was difficult for me to play.
Y ya veía que el fútbol se me acababa, tenía una edad, ya no estaba tan bien físicamente, me costaba jugar.
教练们，尤其是最后几年，
And always the coaches, those last years especially,
Y siempre los entrenadores, esos últimos años sobre todo,
他们向我咨询，我也向他们咨询，我们谈论了很多关于足球的事情。
They consulted me, I consulted with them, we talked a lot about football.
Me consultaban, yo consultaba con ellos, charlábamos mucho de fútbol.
好吧，这几乎是一名前球员参与了
and well it was almost a former player involved in a
y bueno era era casi un un ex jugador metido metido en un
在阿拉西奥和亚特兰大的一个小组中，他是这样认为的。
in a group, both in Alasio and in Atalanta, he considered it that way.
en un grupo, tanto en el Alasio como en la Atalanta, lo consideraba así.
尽管当我必须上场时，我总是在上场时间里付出两分钱。
Although when I had to play, the minutes I got I always gave my two cents.
Aunque cuando tenía que jugar, los minutos que me tocaba siempre daba mi granito de arena.
特别是从经验来看，而不是从外表来看，但早在 2005-2006 年我就已经在我的脑海里开始了。
especially from experience, not so much from physical appearance, but back in 2005-2006 I already had it in my head to start.
sobre todo por experiencia, no tanto por físico, pero sí allá por el 2005-2006 yo ya tenía en la cabeza empezar.
2006年，我们来了。
2006 here we are.
2006 fui a Weham.
何塞要求你去维汉姆，否则你就会错过世界杯。
José asks you to go to Weaham because otherwise you would miss the World Cup.
que te pide José que vayas a Weaham porque si no te parías el mundial.
是的，好吧，我在拉科鲁尼亚待了将近 10 年，当时在拉科鲁尼亚的教练告诉我
Yes, well, I had been in La Coruña for almost 10 years and the coach from that time in La Coruña told me
Sí, bueno, yo venía de 10 años casi en La Coruña y el entrenador de esa época en La Coruña me dice
他告诉我他要打双防，我告诉他，看，我从不自私，我从没想过。
He told me that he was going to play double defense and I told him, look, I was never selfish and I never thought.
Me decía que iba a jugar de doble contención y yo le digo mira, yo nunca fui egoísta y nunca pensé.
对我来说，一直都是为团体着想，但这次我必须为自己着想。
For me, I always thought about the group, but this time I have to think about myself.
En mí, siempre pensé en el grupo, pero esta vez tengo que pensar en mí.
我需要踢边锋。
I need to play as a winger.
Necesito jugar de lateral.
去世界杯。
to go to the World Cup.
para ir al Mundial.
竞争非常激烈。
There was enormous competition.
Había una competencia enorme.
而我则不然，如果我不踢边锋的话我就不会去。
And not me, if I didn't play as a winger I wouldn't go.
Y yo no, si no jugaba de lateral no iba.
嗯，十二月...
Well, in December...
Bueno, en diciembre de...
那一年出现了去西汉姆联的可能性，因为有效力西汉姆联队的捷克人托马斯·雷普卡回到了自己的国家。
That year the possibility of going to West Ham arose, because there was Tomás Repka, a Czech who played for West Ham and returned to his country.
De ese año se abre la posibilidad de ir al West Ham, porque estaba Tomás Repka, un checo que jugaba en el West Ham y se volvía a su país.
在市场的最后一天，我去了盖哈尔踢球，踢了所有必要的比赛，以便能够参加世界杯并走到最后。
And on the last day of the market I went to Guéjar to play, to play all the necessary games to be able to go to the World Cup and to the end.
Y en el último día de mercado me fui a Guéjar a jugar, a jugar todos los partidos necesarios para poder ir al Mundial y al final.
我能得到它。
I could get it.
lo pude conseguir.
这是我的梦想，我相信这是最后的比赛机会。
It was the dream and I believed it was the last chance to play.
Era el sueño y yo creía que era la última oportunidad de poder jugar.
作为一名球员参加过世界杯，我很幸运能够获得它。
a World Cup as a player and well I was lucky enough to get it.
un Mundial como jugador y bueno tuve la suerte de darse.
作为一名球员，你经历过多少情况，对你后来作为教练和球员管理球队有帮助？
How many situations that you experienced as a player later helped you manage the group as a coach and the players?
¿Cuántas situaciones que viviste como jugador después te sirvieron para el manejo del grupo como entrenador y a los futbolistas?
一切，无论好坏。
all, both the good and the bad.
todas, tanto las buenas como las malas.
你总是必须参考并看看如何......确实，每个人都以同样的方式同化我们，这取决于你与谁交谈或与谁交谈。
You always have to take reference and see how... It is true that everyone assimilates us in the same way and it is seen depending on who you talk to or with whom.
Siempre hay que tomar referencia y ver cómo lo... Es verdad que todo el mundo nos asimila igual y se ve según con quién hablás o con quién.
正如你所说
as you spoke
como hablaste.
不一样，但我所做的所有决定，我们所做的所有事情
It's not the same, but all the decisions I've made, all the things we've done
no es lo mismo, pero todas las decisiones que he tomado, todas las cosas que hemos hecho
我做这件事时总是想着如果轮到我或者别人对我说的话会发生什么。
I always do it thinking about what would have happened if it was my turn or if it was said to me.
la hago siempre pensando en qué hubiera pasado si me tocaba a mí o que me la digan a mí.
正如我告诉你的那样，了解距离，有人可以采取这种或另一种方式，但总是......
Knowing the distances, as I tell you, that someone can take it one way or another, but always...
Sabiendo las distancias, como te digo, que alguno puede tomarlo de una manera u otra, pero siempre...
前面的真相，但总是，总是来自我与其他教练的经历。
with the truth ahead, but always, always from the experiences I have had with other coaches.
con la verdad por adelante, pero siempre, siempre de las experiencias que he tenido con otros entrenadores.
教练必须接受
The coach has to accept
El entrenador tiene que aceptar
在特定情况下这对足球运动员来说是不公平的。
that it is going to be unfair to a footballer in a particular situation.
que va a ser injusto con algún futbolista en alguna situación particular.
是的，是的，从这个角度来看，这是不公平的……
Yes, yes, it will be unfair from the point of view that...
Sí, sí, que va a ser injusto desde el punto de vista que...
该球员也许值得参加某场比赛......
that player maybe deserves to play in a certain...
que ese jugador a lo mejor merece jugar en cierta...
在某些时刻，但我们也知道他们要打十一场比赛，这就是我们总是告诉他们的，尤其是在像阿根廷这样的球队中，
at certain moments but also knowing that they play eleven and that is what we always tell them and especially in a team like Argentina where there are
en ciertos momentos pero también sabiendo que juegan once y es lo que siempre le decimos y sobre todo en una selección como argentina donde hay
令人难以置信的水平，而你却被伟大的球员排除在外，所以
an incredible level and you are left out with great players so for
un nivel increíble y te quedan afuera grandes jugadores entonces por
幸运的是，他们懂得平衡，懂得如何玩。
Luckily they have understood balance, how to want to play.
suerte ellos han entendido lo del equilibrio, lo de cómo querer jugar.
当平衡被打破时，我们的表现通常不会很好。
and that when the balance is broken it usually hasn't gone well for us.
y que cuando se rompe el equilibrio normalmente no nos ha ido bien.
在结果层面，但在比赛层面。
at the level of results, but at the level of play.
a nivel de resultados, sino a nivel de juego.
当我们打破了我们的比赛方式时，我们的表现并不好，然后就这样了。
When we broke our way of playing, it didn't go well for us and then that.
Cuando hemos roto nuestra manera de jugar, no nos fue bien y entonces eso.
它可以帮助大家理解我们的理解方式。
It helps everyone understand our way of understanding.
va ayudando a que todo el mundo entienda nuestra manera de entender.
但体育领域的不公正现象仍将继续存在。
but sporting injustices will continue to exist.
pero las injusticias deportivas seguirán estando.
这是非常清楚的。
That is very clear.
Eso es clarísimo.
你如何向球员解释他不会参加比赛？
And how do you explain to the player that he is not going to play?
¿Y cómo le explicás al jugador que no va a jugar?
我说简单是从不得不说的角度来说的。
I say easy and easy from the point of view that it has to be told.
Digo fácil y fácil desde el punto de vista que hay que decírselo.
但你的内部流程一定更复杂。
But your internal process must be more complicated.
Pero el proceso interno tuyo debe ser más complicado.
最糟糕的是最糟糕的我们，好吧，它已经被看到了，我已经为此哭泣了，我们已经
the worst the worst we, well, it has been seen, I have cried with it, we have
lo peor lo peor nosotros yo bueno se ha visto he llorado con ello hemos
我们和他们拥抱过，早上我们有时也和他们争论过。
We have hugged with them, we have argued at times with them in the morning.
Nos hemos abrazado con ellos, hemos discutido en algunos momentos con ellos por las despiertas.
给出的解释，我想我总是明白的是，也许当你告诉他这件事的那一刻
explanations given and I think what I always take away is that maybe the moment you tell him the thing
explicaciones dadas y creo que lo que yo siempre rescato que a lo mejor al momento que le decís la cosa
该玩家不理解它，但是第二天或者当你在下一个电话中看到他时就理解了它，因为最终他看到了
that player does not understand it, but the next day or when you see him the next call understands it, because in the end he sees that
ese jugador no lo entiende, pero al otro día o cuando lo ves la próxima convocatoria lo entiende, porque al final ve que
你想要的就是对团队最好的。
What you want is the best for the team.
uno lo que quiere es lo mejor para el equipo.
但确实感觉这件事发生在我身上。
But it is true that it feels like it happened to me.
Pero sí es verdad que lo siento como si me pasara a mí.
这就是为什么我们与他们如此接近。
That's why we are so close to them.
Por eso somos tan cercanos a ellos.
你知道我想到的保罗·迪巴拉是谁，你和他有关系……
You know who I think of in Paulo Dybala, with whom you have a relationship...
Sabes en quién pienso en Paulo Dybala, con el que tenés una relación...
非常深入，因为你是国家队的一员，而他是最早的球员之一
very deep since you are part of the national team and he is one of the first players who
muy profunda desde que sos parte del seleccionado y él es uno de los primeros jugadores que
表示支持。
that expresses its support.
que expresa su respaldo.
我记得他们与哥伦比亚队的一场比赛，他们一起发表的声明几乎就像是一个声明。
I remember a game they played with Colombia, which they made almost like a statement together.
Me acuerdo de un partido que juegan con Colombia, que hacen casi como una declaración juntos.
保罗离开国家队又回到国家队，这一切都意味着什么。
and Paulo went and returned from the national team with all that that implies.
y Paulo fue y volvió del seleccionado con todo lo que eso implica.
是的，巴勃罗，除了是一名伟大的球员之外，因为他确实是。
Yes, Pablo, in addition to being a great player, because he is.
Sí, Pablo, además de ser un gran jugador, porque está.
我说他是一名伟大的球员，但有时他不参加比赛，有时甚至没有参加杯赛，这有点奇怪。
It's a little strange that I say he's a great player, but sometimes he doesn't play and sometimes he hasn't even come to the Cup.
Es un poco extraño que yo diga que es un gran jugador, pero a veces no juega y a veces incluso no ha venido a la Copa.
但它忠实地反映了理解情况的含义，尤其是爱的含义。
but it is the faithful reflection of what it means to understand the situation and, above all, what it means to love.
pero es el fiel reflejo de lo que es entender la situación y sobre todo lo que es querer.
祝您的团队和员工一切顺利。
May things go well for your team and your people.
que le vaya bien a tu selección y a tu gente.
很多时候他有机会上场，但他没有上场，因为我做了其他决定。
A lot of times he has had the opportunity to play, he has not played because I have made other decisions.
Un montón de veces él ha tenido la oportunidad de jugar, no ha jugado porque yo he tomado otras decisiones.
我所做的决定总是告诉他们原因。
And the decisions I have made I have always told them why.
Y las decisiones que he tomado siempre se las he dicho el porqué.
他已经理解了它们。
and he has understood them.
y las ha entendido.
很难找到像他这样的人，因为他是一名顶级球员，他是最好的球员之一。
It is difficult to find people like him, because he is a top player, he is one of the best players.
Es difícil encontrar personas como él, porque es un jugador top, es un jugador de los mejores.
以及谁了解目前的情况。
and who understands the current situation.
y que entiende la situación del momento.
我们和他在一起。
And we are with him.
Y nosotros estamos con él.
永远感激他所做出的贡献，因为每次他参加我们的通话以及每次比赛
eternally grateful for how he has contributed, because every time he has been in our calls and every time he has played
eternamente agradecido por cómo se ha aportado, porque cada vez que ha estado en las convocatorias nuestras y cada vez que ha jugado
一直是关键，对我们来说他是一个男孩
has been key and for us he is a boy who
ha sido clave y para nosotros es un chico que
不管是否在会议结束后重新估价，我认为我们
that is revalued beyond the minutes or not, I think that we
que es recontravalorado más allá de los minutos o no, creo que nosotros
我们重视他，因为他是一个不可思议的人。
We value him as he is as an incredible person.
Lo valoramos como es como como persona increíble.
你对他留在罗马的决定有什么影响吗？
Did you have anything to do with his decision to stay in Rome?
Tuviste algo que ver en su decisión de que se quedara en Roma?
不，他已经宣称他也在考虑选择。
No, he has declared that he was also thinking about the selection.
No, él ha declarado que también pensaba en la selección.
我们等着看有什么决定。
We waited to see what decision there was.
Nosotros esperábamos a ver qué decisión había.
它非常勇敢，因为今天
and it has been very brave because today
y ha sido muy valiente porque hoy en día
这些决定并不丰富。
These decisions are not abundant.
No abundan estas decisiones.
爱，住在一个你被爱的地方，即使他们可能会为你提供其他地方
of love, of staying in a place where you are loved even though somewhere else they may offer you
de amor, de quedarse en un lugar donde sos querido a pesar de que en otro lugar a lo mejor te ofrecen
我不知道有多少次，对他而言，这是一个不好的决定。
I don't know how many more times, it is a decision, on his part, that was not good.
no sé cuántas veces más, es una decisión, por su parte, que no era buena.
他仍然按照他的要求扩展他的本质，对我们来说，重要的是他
He still enlarges what he is as he asks and for us it is important that he
agranda todavía lo que es como como pide y para nosotros es importante que él se
继续保持高水平的表现，并继续为一支优秀的球队效力。
continue showing at high levels and continue playing for a team that is one of the good ones.
se siga mostrando en los grandes niveles y siga jugando en un equipo que es de los buenos.
我要回马略卡岛了，你们指示的伙计们。
I'm going back to Mallorca, you directed guys.
Vuelvo a Mallorca, dirigiste chicos.
有一个名为 Lionel Scaloni 的技术培训学院。
There is a technical training campus called Lionel Scaloni.
Hay un campus de tecnificación llamado Lionel Scaloni.
你每天都会和 9 岁到 14 岁的孩子一起去山上度假。
You went every day to a hill on vacation with kids from 9 to 14.
Ibas todos los días a una colina de vacaciones con chicos de 9 a 14.
你记得很深情，他也很高兴。
You remember that fondly, he was happy that way too.
Lo recordás con cariño eso, era feliz también así.
是的，我记得……我也有这张图……
Yes, I remember... I also have the image...
Sí, lo recuerdo... Aparte tengo la imagen...
还在脑子里。
Still in the head.
En la cabeza todavía.
马略卡岛夏天非常热，非常潮湿，我们都冻僵了。
Mallorca is very hot in summer, very humid and we were freezing.
Mallorca hace mucho calor en verano, mucha humedad y estábamos heladas.
每天早上八点三十分到下午两点三十分，孩子们在那里做
eight thirty in the morning until two thirty in the afternoon every day with kids there doing
ocho y media de la mañana hasta las dos y media de la tarde todos los días con chicos ahí haciendo
一个我们真正想做的校园
a campus that we really wanted to do
un campus que nosotros lo que queríamos hacer realmente
这不是一个场地，而是让孩子们来进行一种技术培训。
It was not a field, but for the kids to come and do a kind of technical training.
no era un campo, sino que los chicos vengan a hacer una especie de tecnificación.
那是一个月，事情相当激烈。
and it was a month and something quite intense.
y fue un mes y algo bastante intenso.
我刚刚停止踢球，需要与足球保持联系。
I had just stopped playing and needed to stay connected to football.
Yo acababa de dejar de jugar y necesitaba seguir conectado con el fútbol.
我对哪里不感兴趣。
And I wasn't interested in where.
Y no me interesaba dónde.
我不在乎。
I didn't care.
No me importaba.
它是一个球就足够了。
It is enough that it is a ball.
Basta que sea una pelota.
和人们一起玩耍，我很高兴也很幸运
and people playing around, I was happy and luckily
y gente jugando alrededor, era feliz y por suerte
我没有断开连接，我没有关闭开关，因为我想......
I didn't disconnect, I didn't turn off the switch because I think...
No me desconecté, no apagué el interruptor porque creo que...
这很重要，因为之后是一个复杂的时刻，一个没有人为你准备的困难时刻。
It is important because the after is a complicated moment, a difficult moment that no one prepares for you.
Es importante porque el después es un momento complicado, un momento difícil que ninguno te prepara.
突然灯灭了，你不知道该怎么办。
And suddenly the light goes out and you don't know what to do.
Y de repente se apaga la luz y no sabes qué hacer.
在那种情况下，我很清楚我想继续与足球保持联系。
In that case, I was clear that I wanted to remain linked to football.
Yo en ese caso tenía claro que quería seguir vinculado al fútbol.
以任何方式然后
in any way and then
de la manera que sea y que después
如果在某个时候我很幸运或者有机会执导，请做好准备。
If at some point I was lucky or had the opportunity to direct, be prepared.
Si en algún momento me tocaba la suerte o me tocaba la posibilidad de dirigir, estar preparado.
退休后你受过苦吗？
Did you suffer post-retirement?
¿Sufriste el post-retiro?
如果我告诉你，我并不是通过与很多同事或前同事交谈来欺骗你。
If I tell you, I'm not lying to you by talking to a lot of colleagues or ex-colleagues.
Si te digo que no te miento hablando con un montón de compañeros o excompañeros.
我会告诉你，不是很多人，但我确实遭受过这种痛苦。
I would tell you not next to a lot of them, no, but I did suffer from it.
te diría que no al lado de un montón de ellos, no, pero sí que yo lo sufrí.
有些时刻。
There are moments that.
Hay momentos que.
最重要的是你不知道该怎么做。
that you don't know what to do, above all.
que no sabes qué hacer, sobre todo.
你的头，你的头已经准备好在午睡时休息了。
your head, your head is ready to rest in the afternoon nap for.
tu cabeza, tu cabeza está preparada para descansar en la siesta de la tarde para.
和你的孩子一起去散步，只要走一点点，因为你不会太累。
to go for a walk with your children, just a little walk, because you won't get too tired.
para dar una vuelta con tus hijos, una vueltita nada más, porque no cansarte mucho.
早点吃晚饭，为第二天的训练做好准备。
Have dinner early and be prepared for training the other day.
cenar temprano y estar preparado para el entrenamiento del otro día.
当他们把它从你身上夺走时
When they take it out of you
Cuando ellos te lo sacan
当你度假时，他们会把它拿出来一段时间。
They take it out for a while when you're on vacation.
Te lo sacan por un tiempo cuando estás de vacaciones.
你玩了，你知道一个月后你就会回来。
You play and you know that in a month you will return.
Vos jugás y sabés que en un mes volvés.
但当你把它拿出来超过一个月或两个月时，你的头脑会说，现在我该怎么办？
But when you take it out for more than a month or two months, your head says, now what do I do?
Pero cuando te lo sacan más de un mes o dos meses, ya la cabeza dice y ahora qué hago?
你必须做好准备。
and you have to be prepared.
y hay que estar preparado.
幸运的是我很清楚
Luckily I was clear that
Yo por suerte tenía claro que
我想与足球保持联系，我发现骑自行车的爱好对我有帮助，尽管它可能看起来有点
I wanted to stay linked to football, I have found the hobby of cycling that has helped me, although it may seem a little
quería seguir vinculado al fútbol, he encontrado la afición a la bicicleta que me ha ayudado, aunque parezca algo
这与它无关，它对我有很大帮助。
which has nothing to do with it, it has helped me a lot.
que no tiene nada que ver, a mí me ha ayudado un montón.
我本来想稍后再问你的，但你却主动提出了这个话题。
I was going to ask you later, but you brought up the topic.
Te lo iba a preguntar más adelante, pero trajiste vos el tema.
骑自行车对你来说意味着什么？
What does cycling mean to you?
¿Qué significa el ciclismo para vos?
好吧，老实说，今天当我还是一名球员时，我们观看了环法自行车赛
Well, honestly, today when I was a player and we watched the tour de France in
bueno yo sinceramente hoy cuando cuando era jugador y mirábamos el tour de francia en
在六月、七月，我说这些人骑自行车七、八个小时。
In June, July, I say these guys are on a bicycle for seven, eight hours.
En junio, julio, digo estos tipos arriba de una bicicleta siete, ocho horas.
真无聊。
What a bore.
Qué aburrimiento.
今天我说。
And today I say.
Y hoy digo.
我错了，因为这是一项精彩的运动，它是一项
How wrong I was because it is a wonderful sport, it is a sport that
que equivocado estaba porque es un deporte maravilloso es un deporte que
对于我们这些达到一定水平的球员来说。
For us who were players of a certain level.
Para nosotros que fuimos jugadores de cierto nivel.
你正在骑自行车与自己竞争。
You are competing against yourself on a bicycle.
estás compitiendo contra contra vos mismo arriba de una bicicleta.
也就是说，当你累了的时候。
That is, when you are tired.
O sea, cuando estás cansado.
你非常清楚自己的极限，当你身体健康时，你也很清楚自己能走多远。
You know very well the limits you have and when you are well you know very well how far you can go.
Sabes muy bien los límites que tenés y cuando estás bien sabes muy bien hasta dónde puedes llegar.
在维吉莱塔上方，你可以想，你要去山上，从山上你停下来思考风景并思考更多。
And above Vigileta you can think, you are going to the mountain and from the mountain you stop and contemplate the landscape and think more.
Y arriba de Vigileta puedes pensar, te vas a la montaña y desde la montaña para y contempla el paisaje y pensás más.
关于你的球队，关于你的对手，关于如何准备比赛。
on your team, on your rival, on how to prepare for the game.
en tu equipo, en tu rival, en cómo preparar el partido.
它让我头脑清醒了很多，它让我清醒了很多。
It cleared my mind a lot, it cleared me up a lot.
A mí me despejó mucho, me despejó un montón.
它现在可以作为一种治疗手段吗？它已经可以用于分析了吗？
Does it serve you now as therapy and is it already a possibility for analysis?
¿Te sirve ahora como terapia y ya está como posibilidad de análisis?
我用它来解决家庭问题之外的问题，我认为这对于拥有一个家庭至关重要......
I use it for that, beyond the family issue, which I think is essential to have a family that...
Lo utilizo para eso, más allá del tema familiar, que creo que es fundamental tener una familia que te...
支持这一点，因为骑自行车最多也就 4 或 5 个小时。
Support that because by bike you'll go 4 or 5 hours at best.
Soporte eso porque en bici te vas 4 o 5 horas a lo mejor.
我的妻子理解这一点，她知道这对我有好处。
My wife understands it, she knows it's good for me.
Mi esposa lo entiende, sabe que me hace bien.
我正在努力确保我的孩子们也喜欢骑自行车这项运动。
I am trying to make sure that my children also like cycling, their sport.
a mis hijos los estoy intentando que ellos les guste también el ciclismo su deporte
与足球无关，但从你的角度来看，这很精彩。
Nothing to do with football, but wonderful from the point of view you go from.
Nada que ver al fútbol, pero maravilloso desde el punto de vista que vas.
不断地思考，你走到户外，同时进行训练。
Thinking continuously, you go outdoors and at the same time you train.
pensando continuamente, vas al aire libre y a la vez vas entrenando.
你知道谁迷上了自行车吗？
Do you know who got hooked on cycling?
¿Sabés quién se enganchó con el ciclismo?
马努·西诺维尔也是。
Manu Sinoville too.
Manu Sinovili también.
是的，我看到了。
Yes, I saw it.
Sí, lo vi.
我看到一些他骑自行车的照片。
I saw some images of him on a bike.
Lo vi alguna imagen en bici.
好吧，我希望有一天能找到它。
Well, I hope one day to find it.
Bueno, espero algún día encontrarlo.
我认为这是一项做到了这一点的运动
I think it is a sport that has done that
Creo que es un deporte que al que ha hecho ese
一项高性能运动会吸引您的注意力，并让您有机会
A high-performance sport attracts your attention and gives you the opportunity to
un deporte en alto rendimiento te llama mucho la atención y te da la posibilidad de
我不知道，我会在这里，然后是在海滩上，然后是在山里。
I don't know, I'm going to be here, then it's on the beach, then it's in the mountains.
No sé, voy a estar acá, después está en la playa, después está en la montaña.
停下来，喝杯咖啡，想很多。
Stop, have a coffee, think a lot.
Parar, tomás un café, pensar mucho.
我喜欢它。
I like it.
A mí me gusta.
嗯，技术培训校园，Son Caliu 的孩子们，
Well, the technical training campus, the kids in Son Caliu,
Bueno, el campus de tecnificación, los chicos en Son Caliu,
这是您作为教练的第一步。
These are your first steps as a coach.
Son tus primeros pasos como entrenador.
然后你开始在技术团队中工作。
Then you start working in technical teams.
Después empezás a trabajar en cuerpos técnicos.
我想看看你是否记得克劳迪奥·伊塔韦斯说的那一刻，我需要你在村公所。
And I want, to see if you remember, the moment in which Claudio Itávez says, I need you at the village hall.
Y quiero, a ver si te acordás, el momento en el que Claudio Itávez dice, te necesito en la alcudía.
在喀山输给法国之后。
after what had been the defeat in Kazan against France.
después de lo que había sido la derrota en Kazan contra Francia.
你还记得那一刻吗？
Do you remember that moment well?
¿Vos te acordás bien de ese momento?
是的，我清楚地记得我告诉他的话
yes well I remember well what I told him
sí bueno me acuerdo bien que yo le dije
Chiqui，我不想离开国家队，我想留下来，我可以为国家队所用，因为我觉得
Chiqui, I didn't want to leave the national team, I wanted to stay, I was at the disposal of the national team because I felt that
Chiqui que no me quería ir de la selección, que me quería quedar, que estaba a disposición de la selección porque sentía que
我可以做出贡献，我的位置可以在那里，我喜欢指导
that I could contribute and that my place could be there, that I loved directing the
que podía aportar y que mi lugar podía estar ahí, que me encantaba dirigir las
年轻人，因为当时我们就押注于此。
the youth ones, because at that time we were betting on that.
las juveniles, porque en ese momento apostábamos a eso.
好吧，与此同时，几天后，15 或 20 天，阿尔库迪亚锦标赛出来了，没有人指导，我
And well, at the same time, after a few days, 15 or 20 days, the Alcúdia tournament came out, there was no one to direct it and I
Y bueno, al tiempo, a los días, 15 o 20 días, salió el torneo de Alcúdia, que no había quien lo dirija y me
问我是否想执导。
asked if I wanted to direct it.
preguntado si yo quería dirigirlo.
但当然，步行，好吧，我们和巴勃罗在一起，巴勃罗也在青年队。
But of course, walking and well, we were with Pablo, Pablo was also in the youth teams.
Pero claro, caminando y bueno, estábamos con Pablo, que Pablo estaba también en las juveniles.
我们很快就与 Luifa 组建了一支快速教练组，他今天是我们的体能教练 Martín Tocali，他是……
and we quickly put together an express coaching staff with Luifa, who today is our physical trainer, Martín Tocali, who was...
y armamos rápidamente un cuerpo técnico express con Luifa, que hoy es nuestro preparador físico, Martín Tocali, que fue...
作为弓箭手在入口处陪伴我们的人
the one who accompanied us at the entrance as an archer and
el que nos acompañó de entrada de arquero y
对我来说，这是一次快速学习，但当然，我有很多头脑。
And for me it was an express learning, but of course, I came with a lot of head.
Y para mí fue un aprendizaje exprés, pero claro, yo venía con mucha cabeza.
他想做并渴望做出贡献的事情。
in what he wanted to do and eager to contribute.
en lo que quería hacer y con muchas ganas de aportar.
让孩子们了解穿上国家队球衣是什么感觉。
and make the boys understand what it was like to wear the national team shirt.
y hacerle entender a los chicos lo que era vestir la camiseta de la selección.
对我来说这是一件美妙的事情。
For me it was something wonderful.
Para mí fue algo maravilloso.
你还记得第一个清单吗？
Do you remember the first list?
¿Te acordás de la primera lista?
还有奥古斯丁·阿尔门德拉、科利迪奥……
There was Agustín Almendra, Colidio...
Estaba Agustín Almendra, Colidio...
我认为普尔托扑出了对乌拉圭的点球，科林的进球
I think of Purtó saving the penalties against Uruguay and Colín's goals
pienso en Purtó atajando los penales contra Uruguay y los goles de Colín
在那场决赛中，马林内里队对阵俄罗斯队。
of Marinerie against Russia in that final.
de Marinerie contra Rusia en esa final.
一支非常优秀的球队，拥有优秀的球员。
a very good team with great players.
un muy buen equipo con grandes jugadores.
他们立即感受到了穿着国家队球衣踢球的感觉，因为阿尔库迪亚锦标赛不是锦标赛，这不是锦标赛
They immediately felt what it is like to play with the national team's shirt because the Alcudia tournament is not a tournament, it is not a tournament
en seguida sintieron lo que es jugar con la camiseta de la selección porque el torneo de alcudia no es un torneo no es un torneo
又是熟悉的，但也有规则，或者说有奇怪的规则。
It's familiar again, but it also has rules or had strange rules.
recontra conocido, pero además tiene reglas o tenía reglas raras.
是的，场地更小，人造的外观，但我们对待它就像去参加 U-20 世界杯一样。
Yes, the smaller field, that synthetic appearance, but we approach it as if we had gone to play in the U-20 World Cup.
Sí, la cancha más chica, ese aspecto sintético, pero nosotros lo afrontamos como si hubiéramos ido a jugar el Mundial de la Sub-20.
男孩们就是这样面对的。
and the boys faced it that way.
y los chicos lo afrontaron de esa manera.
我们让他明白
We made him understand
Se lo hicimos entender
这几乎没有发生，我记得，我记得一个非常美好的时刻，因为我们进行了合成训练……
It barely happened and I remember, I remember a very good moment because we trained on the synthetic for...
apenas pasó y recuerdo, recuerdo un momento muy bueno porque entrenábamos en el sintético para...
习惯它
get used to it
acostumbrarnos.
当需要列出名单时，我记得我们遗漏了恩佐·贝雷内切亚（Enzo Berenechea），他是所有人中最年轻的。
When it was time to give the list, to leave out, I remember that we left out Enzo Berenechea, who was the youngest of all.
el momento de dar la lista, de dejar afuera, me acuerdo que dejamos afuera a Enzo Berenechea, que era el más joven de todos.
今天我们决定把他排除在外，因为他的水平非常好。
And we decided to leave him out today, since he is at a very good level.
Y decidimos que él quede afuera hoy, que está en un muy buen nivel.
您正在做出且必须做出的第一个决定。
first decisions that you are making and that had to be made.
primeras decisiones que vas tomando y que había que hacerlas.
而能够赢得比赛之后，虽然我说这对我们来说并不重要，但它给了我们很好的推动。
and after being able to win the tournament, although I say it was not important to us, it gave us a good boost.
y después haber podido ganar el torneo, aunque digo no era importante a nosotros, nos dio un buen empujón.
并了解国家队小伙子们的发展道路。
and know what the path of the boys from the national team was.
y saber cuál era el camino de los chicos de la selección.
或者任何想穿这件衬衫的人。
or whoever wants to wear the shirt.
o quien quiera vestir la camiseta.
此外，比赛在 Tennisport 上转播，请参见此处。
In addition, the tournament is broadcast on Tennisport, seen here.
Además, el torneo se transmite por Tennisport, se vio acá.
这是继俄罗斯队和喀山队被淘汰之后，与阿根廷队的第一次接触。
and it is the first contact with an Argentine team after what had been Russia and the elimination in Kazan.
y es el primer contacto con una selección argentina después de lo que había sido Rusia y la eliminación en Kazan.
在比赛进行到一半或决赛之前 Tapia 告诉你
and in the middle of the tournament or before the final Tapia tells you
y en el medio del torneo o antes de la final Tapia te dice
危地马拉和哥伦比亚是你的，2018 年的第一场比赛。
Guatemala and Colombia are yours, the first games of 2018.
Guatemala y Colombia son tuyos, los primeros partidos del 2018.
首先有一项调查，卢西亚诺·纳基斯（Luciano Nackis）作为经理和我们一起来。
First there is a survey, there was Luciano Nackis who had come with us as a manager.
Primero hay como un sondeo, estaba Luciano Nackis que había venido con nosotros de directivo.
他对我们的想法进行了调查。
and he gives us a survey for what we thought.
y nos hace un sondeo para el que pensábamos.
当然，我认为没有任何疑问。
Sure, and I see no doubt of any kind.
Claro, y no veo duda de ningún tipo.
他几乎没有告诉我，我说是的，卢西亚诺，说是的，没问题。
He barely tells me and I say yes, Luciano, say yes, no problem.
Yo apenas me lo dice y le digo si, Luciano, decíle que sí, sin problema.
我的意思是，我们走吧。
I mean, we go.
O sea, nosotros vamos.
我独自做出决定，没有咨询巴勃罗。
I make the decision alone without having consulted Pablo.
Yo tomo la decisión sola sin haberse consultado a Pablo.
当我对卢西亚诺说这句话时，我从巴勃罗那里走出来，我告诉他，巴勃罗，看，看，他们告诉我们如果我们愿意的话，我告诉他是的，他看着我。
When I say that to Luciano, I go from Pablo, I tell him, Pablo, look, look, they told us if we wanted to, I told him yes, he looks at me.
Cuando le digo eso a Luciano, voy de Pablo, le digo, Pablo, mirá, mirá que nos dijeron si queríamos yo, le dije que sí, me mira.
你知道你疯了，对吧？
You know you're crazy, right?
Sabés que estás loco, ¿no?
好吧，巴勃罗，我认为这是一个好时机，我认为
And well, Pablo, I think it's a good time and I think that
Y bueno, Pablo, yo creo que es un buen momento y creo que
他需要我们，我认为我们可以贡献自己的一份力量。
He needs us and I think we can contribute our part.
nos necesita y creo que nosotros podemos aportar lo nuestro.
他告诉我，我会陪你，来吧，我会安排你去任何地方，然后......
He tells me, I'll accompany you, come on, I'll set you up wherever and...
él me dice yo te acompaño, vamos, te banco donde sea y...
一切都从那里开始。
And it all started there.
Y empezó todo ahí.
第二天，他们告诉我们，我们将参加这两场比赛，这非常疯狂，因为我们仍然必须参加比赛。
The next day they told us that we were going to be in these two games and it was very crazy because we still had to play.
Al otro día nos dijeron que íbamos a estar en estos dos partidos y fue muy loco porque todavía teníamos que jugar.
在阿尔库迪亚的比赛，我们必须在下周给出这两场比赛的成年队名单。
Games in Alcudia and we had to give a list the following week of the senior team for those two games.
Partidos en Alcudia y teníamos que dar una lista la semana siguiente de la selección mayor para esos dos partidos.
传奇的瓦伦西亚海滩漫步之旅就这样开始了。
And here comes the legendary walk along the beaches of Valencia.
Y ahí viene la legendaria caminata por las playas de Valencia.
真正的部分不是我们走，我们走。
The real part is not a we walk and we walk.
La parte real no es una caminamos y vamos caminando.
此外，巴勃罗了解海滩，因为他住在那里。
Besides, Pablo knew the beaches because he lived there.
Aparte, Pablo conocía las playas porque vivió ahí.
我们从一个海滩走到另一个海滩，然后就进入了名单。
and we walk from one beach to another and we make the list.
y vamos caminando de una playa a otra y vamos haciendo la lista.
基于我们认为团队当时需要的东西。
based on what we believed the team needed at that time.
en base a lo que creíamos que necesitaba la selección en ese momento.
即使知道利奥不会来，因为我们做的第一件事......
even knowing that Leo was not going to come, because the first thing we did...
aún sabiendo de que Leo no iba a venir, porque lo primero que hicimos...
在那次通话中，它正在呼唤他。
In that call it was calling him.
En esa convocatoria fue llamarlo a él.
我们和巴勃罗进行了视频通话。
We made a video call with Pablo.
Con Pablo hicimos una videollamada.
和狮子座。
With Leo.
Con Leo.
是的，是的，我们告诉了他情况，我认为他应该知道，因为......
Yes, yes, we told him the situation and I think he deserved to know because...
Sí, sí, le contamos la situación y creo que la merecía saber porque...
因为他是队长，嗯，他很高兴，他开始大笑。
because he was the captain and well, he was happy, he started laughing.
porque era el capitán y bueno, él se puso contento, se empezó a reír.
利奥有何反应？
How did Leo react?
¿Cómo reaccionó Leo?
好吧，他开始大笑，因为从逻辑上讲，这是令人震惊的，那是一个......
Well, he started laughing because logically it was striking, it was a moment that...
Bueno, se empezó a reír porque lógicamente era llamativo, era un momento que...
老实说，我们没想到
honestly it was not expected that we
sinceramente no se esperaba que nosotros
让我们负责，但我们很自然地告诉他，我们说，看，我们将指导这些比赛，我们稍后会看到，但我们需要他知道。
Let's take charge, but we told him naturally, we said, look, we are going to direct these games, we will see later, but we need him to know.
Nos hagamos cargo, pero se lo dijimos con naturalidad, dijimos, mira, vamos a dirigir estos partidos, después se verá, pero necesitamos que lo sepa.
我们的想法是招募他们或者让他们穿着国家队球衣参加比赛。
and that our idea is to recruit or have them play with the national team shirt.
y que nuestra idea es reclutar o que jueguen con la camiseta de la selección.
尽可能多的孩子，因为有六场比赛。
as many kids as possible, because there were six games.
la mayor cantidad de chicos posible, porque eran seis partidos.
之后你们是一场比赛，来的教练会根据所看到的情况做出决定。
and after that you are a match, the coach who comes makes the decision based on what was seen.
y que después de eso sois partido, el entrenador que venga tome la decisión en base a lo que se vio.
一切都非常清楚，非常清楚，正常。
Everything very clear, very told, normal.
Todo muy claro, muy contado, normal.
并支持我们并祝我们好运。
and supported us and wished us luck.
y nos apoyó y nos deseó suerte.
所以这是一个难忘的时刻。
So it was an unforgettable moment.
Así que fue un momento inolvidable.
我想象着利奥的咯咯笑。
I imagine Leo's giggle.
Me imagino la risita de Leo.
我们的关系非常好。
We had a very good relationship.
Teníamos relación muy buena.
当然，这一切他都不知道。
And of course, he didn't know about all this.
Y claro, él no sabía de todo esto.
他睁开眼睛笑起来，就像……好吧，我读了我们拿走的东西，我们接受了，然后……
and he opened his eyes and laughed like... well, I read what we took, we accepted and...
y abrió los ojos y se reía como... bueno, leo lo de tomamos, aceptamos y...
但我认为从这个角度来看他很高兴
But I think he was happy from the point of view that
Pero yo creo que se puso contento desde el punto de vista que
我知道我们想要的是团队的利益，我们想要
I knew that what we wanted was the good of the team, that we wanted
Sabía que nosotros lo que queríamos era el bien de la selección, que queríamos que
做一种，我不说更新，因为最终选择就是不断更新，不断更新
to do a kind of, I don't say renewal, because in the end the selection is continually renewal, it is continually
que hacer una especie de, no digo renovación, porque al final la selección es continuamente renovación, es continuamente
但它确实赋予了它新的面貌，让每个人都感到认同。
But it does give it a new look, so that everyone feels identified.
Pero sí darle un aire nuevo, que todo el mundo se sienta identificado.
在第一个列表中，我看到中场生物类型发生了变化。
In that first list I see a change in what the midfielder biotype is.
En esa primera lista yo veo un cambio en lo que es el biotipo de medio campista.
阿根廷有
Argentina had
Argentina tenía
位置最靠前的中场，更像是五人组，有点偏右，有点偏左。
The most positional midfielder, more like playing as a five, a little to the right, a little to the left.
El mediocampista más posicional, más a jugar de cinco, un poquito a la derecha, un poquito a la izquierda.
哈维尔、马赫、卢卡斯、比格利亚、埃弗·巴内加，甚至恩佐都已经处于他最有位置的版本。
Javier, Maché, Lucas, Biglia, Ever Banega, even Enzo was already in his most positional version.
Javier, Maché, Lucas, Biglia, Ever Banega, hasta incluso Enzo ya estaba en su versión más posicional.
帕拉西奥斯、洛切尔索……出现在第一个名单上。
Palacios, Lochelso... appear on that first list.
En esa primera lista aparecen Palacios, Lochelso...
即使是莱昂德罗·帕雷德斯（Leandro Paredes），他被排除在世界杯之外，但他参加了一些更有活力的比赛，更多的区域。
Even Leandro Paredes, who was left out of the World Cup, but who had been part of some more dynamic games, more area to area.
Incluso Leandro Paredes que se quedó afuera del Mundial, pero que había formado parte de algunos partidos más dinámicos, más de área a área.
然后还有后卫和前锋，但我认为这是质的变化。
Then there are defenders and forwards, but I see there as a qualitative change.
Después hay defensores y delanteros, pero yo veo ahí como un cambio cualitativo.
他们是否已将其注册为选择的需要？
Did they have it registered as a need for the selection?
¿Lo tenían como registrado como una necesidad de la selección?
是的，有点疯狂……
Yes, it's a little crazy...
Sí, es un poco loco la...
决定如何踢球，因为我仍然认为足球属于足球运动员。
The decision of how to play, because I still think that football belongs to the footballers.
La decisión de cómo jugar, porque yo sigo pensando que el fútbol es de los futbolistas.
我听安切洛蒂讲话，我对他非常认同。
And I listen to Ancelotti speak and I feel very identified with him.
Y lo escucho hablar a Ancelotti y me siento muy identificado con él.
安切洛蒂在他效力过的球队中也以同样的方式踢球。
Ancelotti has played in the same way in the teams where he has been.
Ancelotti ha jugado de la misma manera en sus equipos donde ha estado.
这始终取决于球员。
and it has always depended on the players.
y siempre ha dependido de los jugadores.
前几天我听到他说他在埃弗顿踢得更多一些......
I heard him talk the other day saying that at Everton he played a little more...
Lo escuchaba hablar el otro día que decía que en el Everton jugaba un poco más...
直接是因为他有球员可以那样踢球，而且他也曾在其他球队踢过球。
direct because he had players to play like that and that he has played on other teams.
directo porque tenía jugadores para jugar así y que en otros equipos ha jugado.
我对此感到认同。
And I feel identified with that.
Y yo me siento identificado con eso.
我为什么这么说呢？
Why do I say it?
¿Por qué lo digo?
因为当...
Because when...
Porque cuando...
世界杯结束后，统计数据显示，
ends the World Cup, the statistics said that the teams that
termina el Mundial, las estadísticas decían que los equipos que
拥有控球权的球队进展得并不顺利。
that had possession had not gone well that the teams with with.
que tenían posesión no había ido bien que los equipos con con.
更快的转变就有机会获胜。
Faster transitions had a chance to win.
transiciones más rápidas tenían posibilidad de ganar.
我们看到我们可以将快速转换的玩家聚集在一起。
And we saw that we could bring together players with quick transitions.
Y veíamos que nosotros podíamos juntar jugadores con transiciones rápidas.
有帕文，有皮蒂·马丁内斯。
There was Pavón, there was Pitti Martínez.
Estaba Pavón, estaba el Pitti Martínez.
埃尔·帕拉西奥（El Palacio）、罗德里戈·巴塔利亚（Rodrigo Bataglia），这些球员有着不同的踢球方式，另一种切入方式。
El Palacio, Rodrigo Bataglia, players with a different way of playing, another cut.
El Palacio, Rodrigo Bataglia, jugadores de otra manera de jugar, otro corte.
我们的目标是这些游戏。
and we aim a little at those games.
y apuntamos un poco a esos partidos.
很好，玩得有点不同，更快一点，更垂直
good to play a little differently a little faster more vertical
bueno a jugar un poco de otra manera un poco más rápido más vertical
但是，嘿，比赛过去了，我们看到有很多足球运动员，切尔西
But hey, the games go by, we see that there is a good crop of footballers, that the Chelsea
Pero bueno, van pasando los partidos, vamos viendo que hay una buena camada de futbolistas, que los Chelsea
他打得很好，然后罗德里戈出现，沃尔也打得很好。
He played well, then Rodrigo appears, wall played well.
jugaba bien, que después aparece Rodrigo, pared jugaba bien.
我可以欣赏所有其他参加世界杯的人，但是
I can appreciate all the others who were in the World Cup, but
le puedo apreciar a todos los otros que fueron en el Mundial, pero
我们需要通过球变得强大。
that we need to become strong through the ball.
que necesitamos hacernos fuerte a través de la pelota.
如果我们必须改变并回到过去，我们会毫不犹豫地改变
and we had no hesitation in changing if we had to change and go back to
y no tuvimos duda en cambiar si tenía que cambiar y volver a
或者真正寻找团队需要什么。
or really to look for what the team needed.
o realmente a buscar lo que el equipo necesitaba.
我们以这样的方式玩的那六场比赛更加垂直一点
and those six games we played in a way like this a little more vertical a little more
y esos seis partidos jugamos de una manera de esta un poco más vertical un poco más
如果可能的话，尽快看到正前方的弧线。
seeing the arc straight ahead as quickly as possible if possible.
viendo el arco de frente cada vez más rápido posible si se podía.
但我们意识到我们需要别的东西。
but we realized we needed something else.
pero nos dimos cuenta de que necesitábamos otra cosa.
安切洛蒂有句话说，有些教练什么都不做。
There is a phrase from Ancelotti that says there are coaches who do nothing.
Hay una frase de Ancelotti dice hay entrenadores que no hacen nada.
以及其他这样做的人。
and others who do.
y otros que sí.
我是第一组的，上面是这么说的。
I'm from the first group, it says like that.
Soy del primer grupo, dice como que.
我尽可能少地干预，事实是我经常关注他，我是那些认为这样的人之一
I intervene as little as possible and the truth is that I follow him a lot, I am one of those who think that
intervengo lo menos posible y yo la verdad que lo sigo mucho soy de los que piensan de que
尤其是我现在指挥的地方，大多数人都打得很好
especially where I am directing now the majority everyone plays well and
sobre todo donde yo estoy dirigiendo ahora la mayoría juegan bien todos y
他们需要的也许是从对手那里给他两到三个重要的信息
and what they need is maybe to give him two or three important inputs from the rival
y lo que necesitan ellos a lo mejor es darle dos o tres inputs importantes del rival
关于我们想要如何进攻的两三件事，但最后的决定是由他们在场上做出的。
two or three things about how we want to attack, but then the decision is made by them on the field.
dos o tres cosas de cómo queremos atacar, pero después la decisión las toman ellos dentro de la cancha.
对于这种类型的球员来说，这对我来说是基本的。
With this type of players it is basic for me.
con este tipo de jugadores es para mí es básico.
我们拥有什么。
We what we have.
Nosotros lo que hemos.
我们所做的，就是为了达到对他们公平的目标。
built, we have done, is to have reached what is fair to them.
construido, hemos hecho, es haberle llegado lo justo a ellos.
他认为所发生的一切已经足够了。
and that what has come to him was enough.
y que eso que le ha llegado le bastó.
因为如果你转移你看到的所有东西以及所有...
because if you transfer all the things that you see and all the...
porque si le traspasas todas las cosas que vos miras y todas las...
也许是你对游戏的恐惧。
the fears that you have about the game, maybe.
los miedos que vos tenés del partido, a lo mejor.
事情变得很复杂，我们做得不好。
It gets complicated and we don't do it well.
Se le complica y no lo hacemos bien.
所以让我们更加努力吧。
So let's go more for it.
Así que vamos más por lo.
因为这很容易，并且知道他们在球场上做出决定。
because of how easy it is and knowing that they decide on the field.
por lo fácil y sabiendo que ellos deciden dentro de la cancha.
在这种模式的变化中，我最近不得不评论博卡学生队。
Within this change of pattern, I recently had to comment on Estudiantes Boca.
Dentro de ese cambio de patrón, hace poco me tocó comentar Estudiantes Boca.
和加萨门迪亚（Garzamendia）在学生中演奏。
and Garzamendia played in students.
y en estudiantes jugó Garzamendia.
我记得阿萨门迪亚在与巴拉圭的比赛中造成了很大的问题，阿玛尼扑出了点球。
And I remember that Arsamendia caused a big problem in that match with Paraguay and the penalty that Armani saved.
Y yo me acuerdo que Arsamendia causó un problema grande en aquel partido con Paraguay y el penal que ataja Armani.
它将帮助你撤掉劳塔罗并加入迪玛丽亚，迪玛丽亚在那一刻我并不是说他是头号公敌，但几乎是。
and it will help you to remove Lautaro and put in Di María, a Di María who at that moment I am not saying was public enemy number one, but almost.
y te sirva a vos a sacar a Lautaro y a poner a Di María, a un Di María que en ese momento no digo que era enemigo público número uno, pero casi.
在那场以 1 比 1 结束的比赛中
and in that match, which ends 1 to 1,
y en ese partido, que termina 1 a 1,
你解释一下，看，我必须把劳塔罗换下，因为迪马里亚对于防守阿萨门迪亚的那一边很重要。
You explain, look, I had to take Lautaro out because Dimaria was important to defend that side of Arsamendia.
Vos explicás, miren, yo tuve que sacar a Lautaro porque Dimaria era importante para defender ese costado de Arsamendia.
接下来是与卡塔尔的比赛，罗德里戈、莱昂德罗和吉奥，以及梅西、阿奎罗和劳塔罗都在那里踢球。
Then comes the match with Qatar, where Rodrigo, Leandro and Gio, plus Messi, Agüero and Lautaro, play there.
Después viene el partido con Qatar, donde ahí juegan Rodrigo, Leandro y Gio, más Messi, Agüero y Lautaro.
如果你愿意的话，我在与卡塔尔的比赛中看到了这种模式变化的起源。
I kind of see there in that match with Qatar, if you like, the genesis of that change of pattern.
Yo como que veo ahí en ese partido con Qatar, si querés, la génesis de ese cambio de patrón.
是的，也有一些被迫的中断。
Yes, there was also a somewhat forced break.
Sí, hubo un quiebre también un poco forzado.
我们需要获胜并且。
We needed to win and.
Nosotros necesitábamos ganar y.
我们确信这是唯一的比赛方式。
We were convinced that it was the only way to play.
estábamos convencidos que era la única manera de jugar.
我们需要派上那些打得好的、没有烧伤球的人。
We need to put those who played well, who didn't burn the ball.
Necesitamos poner a los que jugaban bien, que no les quemaban la pelota.
并尝试将信誉良好的玩家聚集在一起。
and try to bring together players with good standing.
y intentar juntar jugadores jugadores de buen pie.
那场比赛...我们与卡塔尔队遭遇了麻烦，因为事实是我们...
that match was... we suffered with Qatar, because the truth is that we...
ese partido fue... sufrimos con Catar, porque la verdad que nosotros...
我们不喜欢他们的比赛方式，这是一个运转良好的 3-5-2，非常
We didn't like their way of playing, it was a very well-oiled 3-5-2, very
no nos gustaba la manera de jugar de ellos, era un 3-5-2 muy aceitado, muy
有非常非常明显的运动，这些运动对我们不利，但我们必须冒险，我们必须寻找其他东西，
with very very marked movement and the movements were bad for us but we had to take risks, we had to look for something else and
con movimiento muy muy marcado y que a nosotros nos venían mal los movimientos pero teníamos que arriesgar teníamos que buscar otra cosa y
这就是我告诉你的地方，你非常依赖球员，因为
and that's where I tell you that you depend a lot on the players because
y ahí es donde yo te digo que dependes mucho de los jugadores porque
在正常情况下，那场比赛对我们来说不会顺利，因为我们没有时间准备。
Under normal conditions, that match would not have gone well for us because we had not had time to prepare for it.
condiciones normales ese partido no nos hubiera ido bien porque no habíamos tenido tiempo de prepararlo
他们在球场上解决了我们前几天遇到的任何问题。
and they on the court solved any problem we had had in the previous days.
y ellos dentro de la cancha solucionaron cualquier problema que habíamos tenido en los días anteriores.
在本频道的一次演讲中，针对狮子座，他告诉我们许多人都扮演过 10 号角色。
In a talk for this channel, for the Leo Clan, he told us that many have played as number 10.
En una charla para este canal, para el Clan Leo, nos decía que hayan jugado muchos como número 10.
他甚至包括后来到达的亚历克西斯和恩佐，再加上他、罗德里戈、安赫尔本人、吉奥·洛塞尔索。
and he even included Alexis and Enzo who arrived later, plus him, Rodrigo, Ángel himself, Gio Lo Celso.
y hasta incluyó a Alexis y a Enzo que llegaron después, más él, Rodrigo, Ángel mismo, Gio Lo Celso.
这种功能性足球、短传有帮助。
This functional football, short passes, helps.
Ayuda esto del fútbol funcional, de pases cortos.
一个更具嘲讽性的任期，但同时也试图给对手一个惊喜。
of a more mocking tenure, but at the same time also seeking to surprise the rival.
de una tenencia más burlona, pero al mismo tiempo también buscando sorprender al rival.
与你作为教练开始周期时的直接比赛相去甚远。
far from that direct game with which you began the cycle as a coach.
lejos de ese juego directo con el que vos empezaste el ciclo como entrenador.
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
正如他所说，就像你看他们所有人一样，他们从一开始就开始了一场钩子游戏。
It is just as he said it and it is just as if you look at all of them, they have started a game of hooking in their beginnings in
es tal cual como lo dijo él y es tal cual si miras todos ellos han empezado a un juego de enganche en sus inicios en
甲级联赛，这有助于他们在其他人无法移动和接球的空间中移动
first division and that helps them move in a space where others could not move and receive balls
primera división y eso ayuda a que se mueva en un espacio donde otro no se podría mover reciban balones
在字里行间，他们知道如何移动到另一个正常囚犯会感到不舒服的地方
between the lines they know how to move where another normal inmate would feel uncomfortable
entre líneas se sepan mover donde otro un volante normal un interno normal se sentiría incómodo
我认为他们在那里感觉很好，因为他们已经履行了自己的职责，然后发生了变化。
I think that they feel good there because they have fulfilled their functions and then the change.
Yo creo que ellos ahí se sienten bien porque han cumplido funciones y después el cambio.
每个人的心理变化是知道今天在足球界他们需要完成两到三项功能。
The mental change for each one is knowing that today in football they need to do two or three functions.
El cambio mental de cada uno es saber que hoy en el fútbol necesita hacer dos o tres funciones.
罗德里戈一开始在我们队担任边锋，最后甚至担任双后卫。
Rodrigo started with us as a winger and ended up even playing as double support.
Rodrigo empezó con nosotros de extremo y terminó jugando incluso de doble contención.
他总是这样做，总是很好，总是
and he always does it, always well and always
y lo hace siempre, siempre bien y siempre
尝试，了解球队在每场比赛中需要什么。
trying, knowing what the team needs in each game.
intentando, sabiendo lo que necesita el equipo en cada partido.
同样的亚历克西斯，同样的恩佐，他们会改变，有时一个人踢前锋，另一个人踢后面。
The same Alexis, the same Enzo who change, sometimes one plays forward and another plays behind.
Lo mismo Alexis, lo mismo Enzo que van cambiando, a veces uno juega adelante y otro juega atrás.
但他们始终了解比赛的要求。
but they understand what the game requires at all times.
pero entienden lo que requiere el partido en cada momento.
但最根本的一点是他们是通过球移动的。
But the fundamental thing is that they move through the ball.
Pero lo fundamental es que se muevan a través de la pelota.
它不会打扰任何人，每个人都喜欢它。
It doesn't bother anyone, everyone loves it.
A ninguno le quema, a todos la quieren.
在比赛的那一刻一切就都明白了。
and everything understands at the moment of the game.
y todo entiende en el momento del partido.
我无法向你解释当游戏进行时
I can't explain that to you when a game is being played where
Eso no se lo puedo explicar yo cuando se está jugando un partido donde
移动到哪里。
where to move.
dónde hay que moverse.
他们自己理解这一点，他们意识到这一点，但从根本上我想说，球不会烧伤他们中的任何人。
They understand it on their own, they realize it, but fundamentally I would say that the ball does not burn any of them.
Lo entienden solo, se van dando cuenta, pero fundamental diría yo que la pelota no les quema a ninguno.
但是，比如说决赛对阵哥伦比亚，你有没有做出调整？
But, for example, in the final against Colombia, is there an adjustment that you make?
Pero, por ejemplo, en la final ante Colombia, ¿hay un ajuste que vos hacés?
哥伦比亚队在右路进攻，理查德·里奥斯在那儿，詹姆斯在边路。
Colombia was progressing on the right, Richard Ríos was there, James was on the wing.
Colombia progresaba por la derecha, estaba Richard Ríos, el lateral se tiraba James.
在决赛对阵法国队的比赛中，你是否曾一度将他派到左路的安赫尔？
And at one point you send him to Ángel again on the left with the match against France in the final?
¿Y vos en un momento lo mandás a Ángel de nuevo por la izquierda con el partido ante Francia por la final?
甚至亚历克西斯在与我们的谈话中也强调它是你看到和调整的东西。
Even Alexis, in a talk with us, also highlighted it as something that you saw and adjusted.
hasta incluso Alexis en una charla también con nosotros lo destacó como algo que viste vos y ajustaste.
嗯，是的，但我想每个观看比赛的人都意识到我们那边
Well, yes, but I imagine that everyone who was watching the game was realizing that on that side we
Bueno, sí, pero imagino que todo todo el mundo que había estaba viendo el partido se estaba dando cuenta que por ese lado nosotros
我们进入了，调整不仅仅是考虑防守，当然还有考虑
were entering and the adjustment is not only thinking about defending but also that of course
estaban entrando y el ajuste no es sólo pensando en defender sino también que claro
把迪马利亚这样的球员放在那里，你就必须防守他。
putting a player like Di María there, then you have to defend him.
poniendo un jugador como Di María ahí, después lo tenés que defender vos a él.
这是我们一直押注的一点。
which is a bit of what we always bet on.
que es un poco lo que siempre apostamos.
我们打赌是的，尽量不要让他们伤害我们，但在那之后就意味着扔
We bet that yes, try not to let them hurt us, but after that it means throwing
Apostamos a que sí, intentar que no nos hagan daño, pero después que es tirarle
从球传给他们，或者在这种情况下从安赫尔向前跑。
to them from the ball or in this case from Ángel to run forward.
a ellos desde el balón o en este caso de Ángel que corra para adelante.
这是我们当时需要的调整，因为我们正在受苦。
It was an adjustment that we needed at that time because we were suffering.
Fue un ajuste que lo necesitábamos en ese momento porque estábamos sufriendo.
我认为结果很好，结果很好，特别是因为你有球员能够做这些事情。
And I think it turned out well, it turned out well, especially because you have players to be able to do those things.
y creo que salió bien salió bien sobre todo porque porque tenés jugadores para poder hacer esas cosas
迪玛利亚的命运，无论左还是右，对他来说都是一样的。
Di María's fate, left or right, which is the same for him.
La suerte de Di María, izquierda o derecha, que es igual para él.
将罗德里戈从内线转移到外线。
Move Rodrigo from playing inside to playing outside.
Correr el Rodrigo de jugar adentro a jugar afuera.
这就是国家队所拥有的，这就是这些球员所拥有的，你可以在比赛中改变。
That's what the national team has, that's what these players have that you can change in the middle of a game.
Eso tiene la selección, eso tiene estos jugadores que vas podiendo variar en medio de un partido.
球队防守时看到的一种阵型是4-4-2。
a posture that one sees when the team defends that is 4-4-2.
una postura que uno ve cuando el equipo defiende que es 4-4-2.
后来发现设备坏了。
Then it turns out that the equipment breaks down.
Después se enacata que el equipo se descompone.
当人们掌握球权时，你不知道他们采取什么策略，也不知道他们的电话号码是什么。
When people have the ball you don't know what tactic, what phone number there is.
Cuando la gente tiene la pelota no sabés qué táctica, qué número telefónico hay.
但让我们从防守顺序开始。
But let's start with the defensive order.
Pero empecemos por el orden defensivo.
为什么从4-4-2开始防守？
Why do you start from that 4-4-2 in defense?
¿Por qué partís de ese 4-4-2 en defensa?
算上Leo吧，他是两位常客之一。
counting Leo, who is one of the two regulars.
contando a Leo, que es uno de los dos habituales.
嗯，因为首先我们认为这对我们的玩家有利。
Well, because first we thought it benefited our players.
Bueno, porque primero pensamos que beneficiaba a nuestros jugadores.
总是在读或者不读时不在最后
always being read or not being at the end when not reading
estando siempre leo o no estando al final cuando no está leo
要么是一名中场球员，要么是另一名前锋，我们总是有两名球员。
Either a midfielder plays or another striker plays, we always have two.
o juega un media punta o juega otro delantero, siempre tenemos dos.
然后由于对称性，在我看来，今天的系统
and then because of the symmetry it seems to me that it is the system that today
y después por la simetría me parece que es el sistema que hoy en día
它是最好理解的，如果需要更正，也是最容易纠正的。
The best it is understood and if a correction needs to be made it is the easiest to correct.
mejor se entiende y si hay que hacer una corrección es el más fácil para corregir.
我对称地覆盖了球场，然后如果任何时候我们将两个人之一放在外面
I covered the court symmetrically and then if at any time we with one of the two outside
cubrí simétricamente la cancha y después si en algún momento nosotros con uno de los dos de afuera
如果我们因为必须追一名球员而不得不排成五人阵，那么我们就追一名球员，这样你就只剩下三名中场球员了，因为我们总是有三名中场球员。
If we have to make a line of five because we have to chase one, we chase one and you are left with three midfielders, as we always have three midfielders.
si tenemos que hacer una línea de cinco porque hay que perseguir a uno se persigue y te quedan los tres volantes que siempre tenemos tres volantes de juego
而且总会有 5-3-2 或 3-5-2，无论你怎么称呼它。
and there would always be a 5-3-2 or 3-5-2, whatever you want to call it.
y siempre quedaría un 5-3-2 o 3-5-2, como lo quieras llamar.
我认为这对我们有利，因为我们知道在某些时候我们可以改变。
I think that benefits us, knowing that at some point we can change.
Creo que eso para nosotros nos beneficia, sabiendo que en algún momento podemos cambiar.
我们总是有机会适应这个系统。
We always have the possibility of adapting with that system.
siempre tenemos la posibilidad de adaptarnos con ese sistema.
对我们来说更容易。
For us it is easier.
Para nosotros es más fácil.
然后对于球来说，这更多地取决于他们。
and then with the ball it depends more on them.
y después ya con la pelota depende más de ellos.
玩家可以触摸、移动、解释空间。
of the players to touch and move, interpret spaces.
de los jugadores de tocar y moverse, interpretar espacios.
是的，我们想怎样对付它，就怎样攻击它。
Yes, what we deal with it is how we want to attack it.
Sí, a nosotros lo que le pasamos a ello es cómo lo queremos atacar.
看看我们是否会攻击...
Let's see if we attack...
A ver si atacamos...
2 和 3，有时我们攻击 3 和 2 来建造，但是一旦他们在我们建造时收到它
2 and 3, sometimes we attack 3 and 2 to build, but then once they receive it when we do
2 y 3, a veces atacamos 3 y 2 para construir, pero después una vez que la reciben ellos cuando hacemos
这里的训练课程我们称之为 11 against 0，即
the training sessions here that we call 11 against 0, which is
los entrenamientos acá que le llamamos el 11 contra 0 que es
在没有对手的情况下进行攻击，实际上是靠记忆，知道你的队友在哪里。
attack without rivals, practically by memory, knowing where your teammates are.
atacar sin rivales, prácticamente a memoria, sabiendo dónde están tus compañeros.
我们告诉他们我们想要如何攻击，然后他们根据位置进行移动
We tell them how we want to attack and then they move it based on where
nosotros le decimos cómo queremos atacar y después ellos la van moviendo en base a donde
同伴在哪里但是如果在
where are the companions but if at
donde están los compañeros pero si a la
对手，我们相信我们可以用这种方式伤害他，然后我们给他
the rival and we believe that we can hurt him that way and then we give him the
el rival y creemos que le podemos hacer daño de esa manera y después le damos el
如果这被称为B计划，因为通常那些最近与阿根廷队比赛的球员并没有给我们带来太大改变，那么它就不是
If it is called plan b because normally those who play with Argentina lately are not changing us much, it is not
si se le llama el plan b porque ellos normalmente los que juegan con argentina últimamente no nos están cambiando mucho no es
他们从内部关闭了很多，所以我们给了他们B计划，如果发生这种情况，我们会这样做。
They are closing a lot from the inside and so we give them the plan B that if it happens, we would do this.
están cerrando mucho por dentro y entonces le damos ahí el plan B que si pasaría, haríamos esto.
但最终决定是由他们做出的，但我认为永远都是这样。
But in the end the decisions are made by them, but I think it will always be like that.
pero las decisiones en el final las toman ellos, pero creo que siempre será así.
他们给玩家提供了多少信息？
How much information do they give the players?
¿Cuánta información les dan a los jugadores?
视频，有视频分析。
of video, there is video analysis.
de video, hay videoanálisis.
有，有，有视频分析，但对我们来说，有这个。
There is, there is, there is video analysis, but for us, there is for this.
Hay, hay, hay videoanálisis, pero para nosotros, para ello hay.
过滤。
the filtering.
el filtrado.
过滤是个人还是集体？
And is the filtering individual or collective?
¿Y el filtrado es individual o colectivo?
不，总是集体的，当我们单独谈论时，我们谈论的是......
No, always collective and when we talk individually we talk about players who are...
No, siempre colectivo y cuando hablamos individual hablamos de jugadores que son...
也许未知。
maybe unknown.
a lo mejor desconocidos.
例如，我们对阵加拿大，本来就是我们的对手。
For example, we have played against Canada, which a priori was a rival.
Por ejemplo, hemos jugado contra Canadá, que a priori era un rival.
他知识不多，但我们知道他是一个很难对付的对手。
He didn't have much knowledge, but we knew he was a difficult opponent.
que no tenía mucho conocimiento, pero sabíamos que era un rival difícil.
乔纳森·戴维斯（Jonathan Davies）、里奇·拉里尔（Richie Larier），我的意思是，他们都是非常优秀的球员。
Jonathan Davies, Richie Larier, I mean, there were very good players.
Jonathan Davies, Richie Larier, o sea, había jugadores muy buenos.
所以我们确实要一一分析，展示给玩家看。
So there we did have to analyze one by one and show it to the players.
Entonces ahí sí tuvimos que analizar uno con uno y mostrarle a los jugadores.
哪些可能会给我们带来麻烦，哪些地方可能会给他们带来麻烦？
Which ones could put us in trouble and where we could put them in trouble?
¿Cuáles nos podrían poner en aprieto y dónde nosotros podríamos poner en aprieto a ellos?
但通常当我们与对手或美国人比赛时，尤其是那些更有名的人
but normally when we play against rivals or Americans, especially those who are better known
pero normalmente cuando jugamos contra rivales o americanos sobre todo que son más conocidos
我们分析全球以及他们的优势所在。
We analyze the global and where their strength is.
analizamos lo global y dónde la fortaleza de ellos.
我们可以伤害他的事情，但视频不会持续很长时间，我们不是粉丝
the things where we can hurt him, but the videos don't last long, we are not fans of
las cosas donde le podemos hacer daño, pero no duran mucho los videos, no somos fanáticos de
让玩家在那里停留 20 分钟、25 分钟。
to have the player there for 20 minutes, 25 minutes.
de tener el jugador ahí 20 minutos, 25 minutos.
还有其他教练也这样做。
There are other coaches who do.
Hay otros entrenadores que sí.
我有过教练，他们...
I have had coaches who...
Yo he tenido entrenadores que...
每天有 25 或 30 分钟的视频，效果很好。
which was 25 or 30 minutes of video daily and well.
que diariamente eran 25 o 30 minutos de video y bueno.
如果他们感觉这样舒服，那很好，我们想要的是他们感觉舒服，而不是教练。
And it's good that if they feel comfortable like that, what we want is for them to feel comfortable and not the coach.
Y está bien que si se sienten cómodos así, nosotros lo que queremos es que ellos se sientan cómodos y no el entrenador.
很好，在他们面前发表演讲说很好，我已经告诉过你会发生什么，现在取决于你，不。
being well, giving a talk in front of them to say well, I already told you what is going to happen now it's up to you, no.
estando bien, dando una charla delante de ellos para decir bueno yo ya les dije lo que va a pasar ahora depende de ustedes, no.
我们更愿意清楚地了解他们在场上所说的内容。
We prefer to be clear and what they were saying on the field.
Nosotros preferimos ser claro y que decían ellos dentro de la cancha.
显然，双败淘汰赛的动态是
Obviously, the dynamics of the double elimination date are
Obviamente que la dinámica de la doble fecha eliminatoria es
他们在一场联赛、休息、恢复后抵达。
They arrive after a league game, rest, recovery.
Llegan después de un partido de liga, descanso, recuperación.
余地不多，你可以有机会参加一两次训练，比赛是在周四。
There is not much margin, you can have the chance of one or two training sessions, the game is on a Thursday.
No hay mucho margen, podés tener la chance de uno o dos entrenamientos, el partido es un jueves.
换句话说，这些比赛都在周一、周二进行，而比赛则在周四进行。
In other words, you have them all on Monday, Tuesday and the game is on Thursday.
O sea, los tenés a todos lunes, martes y el partido es el jueves.
你如何准备第一场比赛？与第二场相比有什么不同，你已经从第一场比赛中反弹了？
How do you prepare for that first game and what are the differences compared to the second, where you already have the rebound from the first?
¿Cómo preparas ese primer partido y qué diferencias hay respecto del segundo, donde ya tenés el rebote del primero?
也许双轮第一场比赛已经给你带来了中间的旅行和其他感觉。
perhaps a trip in the middle and other sensations that the first game of that double round already gives you.
quizás un viaje en el medio y otras sensaciones que ya te da el primer partido de esa doble tanda.
你如何准备，如何训练？
How do you prepare, how do you train?
¿Cómo se prepara, cómo se entrena?
嗯，最初是在周一
Well, initially on Monday
Bueno, en principio el día lunes
他们从来都不在那儿。
They are never all there.
Nunca están todos.
希望有 60% 或 70%。
Hopefully there are 60 or 70 percent.
Con suerte hay el 60 o 70 por ciento.
然后我们尽量不去
and then we try not to
y entonces intentamos no
不要谈论我们将如何与对手比赛，直到周二每个人都到齐为止，如果我们在哪里进行第一次谈话
say nothing about how we are going to play against the rival, nothing until everyone is there on Tuesday if we do the first talk where
decir nada de cómo vamos a jugar del rival nada hasta que no estén todos el martes si hacemos la primer charla donde
好吧，如果我们必须谈论发生的事情，我们会谈论并且远远高于我们将要谈论的竞争对手
Well, if we have to talk about what happened, we talk and far above the rival we are going to
Bueno, si hay que hablar de lo que pasó, hablamos y muy por arriba del rival que vamos
周二我们就开始关注如何进攻、我们的比赛方式。
to face and we focus on how we are going to attack, our way of playing, already on Tuesday.
a enfrentar y enfocamos en cómo vamos a atacar, nuestra manera de jugar, ya el martes.
周三是赛前谈话。
And on Wednesday it is the pre-match talk.
Y el miércoles sí es la charla prepartido.
这是我们都需要他们的日子
It's the day we all need them to be
Es el día que todos necesitamos que estén
可用的。
available.
disponibles.
最后，周二的训练进行了一半。
In the end it's half training on Tuesday.
Al final es medio entrenamiento del martes.
这是第二阶段，球员们可以在周三全天做其他事情，但周三的球员也不能做太多事情，因为他在比赛。
which is the second stage where the players can do something else and all day on Wednesday, but the player on Wednesday can't do much either because he plays.
que es la segunda etapa donde ya los jugadores pueden hacer algo más y todo el día del miércoles, pero el del miércoles tampoco puede hacer mucho porque juega.
所以你必须适应。
So you have to adapt.
Entonces hay que adaptarse.
我们已经适应了。
We are already adapted.
Nosotros ya estamos adaptados.
也许是俱乐部教练。
Maybe a club coach.
A lo mejor un entrenador de club.
他会更难适应，因为他需要日常生活，他需要……
It would be more difficult for him to adapt to that because he needs daily life, he needs to be...
le costaría más adaptarse a eso porque necesita el día a día, necesita estar de...
从月亮到星期五和他的球员们在一起。
from moon to Friday with his players.
de luna a viernes con sus jugadores.
对我们来说，这是正常的，我们知道这一点。
For us, that is normal and we know it.
Nosotros eso ya es normal y lo sabemos.
虽然我们真的很想见到他，想训练，但我们知道
Although we really want to see him, to train, we know that
A pesar de que tenemos una gana enorme de verlo, de entrenar, sabemos que
我们必须取决于他们如何到达，而我们的愿望与他们的愿望无关。
We have to depend on how they arrive and our desire is not related to their desire.
tenemos que depender de cómo llegan y nuestras ganas no van relacionadas a las ganas de ellos.
但我们已经吸收了它，有时我们会因为做不到而犹豫不决，对吗？
But we have already assimilated it and sometimes we hold ourselves back from doing things because we can't, right?
pero lo tenemos ya asimilado y a veces nos contenemos en hacer cosas porque no se puede, ¿no?
一个淘汰日期与下一个淘汰日期之间的后续情况如何？
What is the follow-up like between one elimination date and the next?
¿Cómo es el seguimiento entre una fecha eliminatoria y la siguiente?
比赛和联赛如何分配。
how games and leagues are distributed.
cómo se reparten partidos, ligas.
你和玩家聊天，你在新闻或网络上看到一些引起你注意的东西，你就和玩家核实一下。
You chat with the players and you see something in the news or on the networks that catches your attention, you check it with the player.
charlas con los jugadores y ves algo en las noticias o en las redes que te llama la atención, lo chequeas con el jugador.
治疗效果如何？
How is the treatment?
¿Cómo es el trato?
嗯，每个教练组成员都有若干名球员，X 数量。
Well, each member of the coaching staff has a number of players, X amount.
Bueno, nosotros cada miembro de cuerpo técnico tiene una cantidad de jugadores, X cantidad.
球员们，完美。
Players, perfect.
Jugadores, perfecto.
巴勃罗有一个，雷拉尔多有另一个，沃尔特有另一个，马蒂亚斯......
Pablo has one, Reraldo has another, Walter has another, Matías...
Pablo tiene a uno, Reraldo tiene a otro, Walter a otro, Matías...
当有一些新闻时，每个人都会与他们交谈，如果他们不关注
and each one when there is some news talks to them and if they don't follow
y cada uno cuando hay alguna noticia habla con ellos y si no siguen a
他们的球员和他们告诉我们
their players and they tell us
sus jugadores y nos van comentando
如果发生什么事情或者如果他们看到什么事情，他们就会把削减放在我们拥有的小组中。
If something happens or if they see something and they put the cuts in the group that we have.
si pasa algo o si ven algo y van poniendo los cortes en el grupo que tenemos.
而老师就是那个不断地和大家说话的人。
And the teacher is the one who talks to everyone continuously.
Y el profe es el que habla con todos continuamente.
除了马丁在逻辑上属于弓箭手这一事实之外。
beyond the fact that Martín is logically with the archers.
más allá de que Martín lógicamente está con los arqueros.
但我们已经这样了，上油了。
But we have it well like this, well oiled.
Pero lo tenemos bien así, bien aceitado.
每个玩家都非常清楚。
Each player knows very well.
Cada jugador sabe muy bien.
谁会联系他，我想......
who is going to contact him and I think...
quién lo va a contactar y creo que...
这是基本的，当有真正重要的事情时，他们会过滤我的信息。
which is fundamental and they filter my information when there is something really important.
que es fundamental y a mí me filtran la información cuando hay algo realmente importante.
如果没有，想象一下一名有问题的球员出来了，他可能不会在周末参加比赛。
If not, imagine that a player comes out who has a problem and who may not be going to play at the weekend.
Si no, imaginate que sale un jugador que tiene una molestia y que a lo mejor no va a jugar el fin de semana.
三四天前，你已经在考虑他是否还好，他是否会和我们一起参加比赛。
Three or four days before, you're already thinking about whether he's okay, whether he's going to make it to the game with us or not.
tres o cuatro días antes ya estás con la cabeza a ver si está bien, si va a llegar al partido con nosotros o no.
然后我们等到比赛时间。
Then we wait until game time.
Entonces esperamos hasta que llegue el momento del partido.
然后，如果他不参加比赛，他们就会向我提供信息。
Then, if he doesn't play, they give me the information.
Después, si no juega, me pasan la información.
您如何管理 FIFA 日期和 FIFA 日期之间的时间段？
How do you manage the period between FIFA date and FIFA date?
¿Cómo manejas el período entre fecha FIFA y fecha FIFA?
显然你在国家队有活力。
Obviously you have the energy in the national team.
Obviamente estás con la energía en la selección.
你做其他事情，骑自行车，和家人在一起。
You do other things, cycling, you are with your family.
Haces otras cosas, ciclismo, estás con tu familia.
你们两个的时间管理如何？
How is your time management between the two of you?
¿Cómo es la gestión de tu tiempo entre las dos?
上一个国际足联日期和下一个日期？
Previous FIFA date and the next one?
¿Fecha FIFA anterior y la que viene?
幸运的是，每天都有足球比赛，这对我的家人来说并不那么重要。
Luckily, and not so much for my family, there is football every day.
Por suerte, y no tanto para mi familia, hay fútbol todos los días.
然后你就看到了一切。
Then you see everything.
Entonces ves todo.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
一切你能做的。
Everything you can.
Todo lo que pueda.
是的，是的。
Yes, yes.
Sí, sí.
我们看到，我们看到，我们看到。
We see, we see, we see.
Vemos, vemos, vemos.
我们看足球，足球，足球。
We watch football, football, football.
Vemos fútbol, fútbol, fútbol.
我们看到了。
We see.
Vemos.
联赛并不重要，也许我们会看到来自其他联赛的对手或球员。
And the league doesn't matter, maybe we see rivals or players from other leagues.
Y no importa la liga, a lo mejor vemos rivales o jugadores de otras ligas.
我们喜欢不断更新自己，看看这是否适合我们的团队。
We like to continually update ourselves and see if that works for our team.
Nos gusta ir continuamente actualizándonos y ver si eso nos sirve para nuestro equipo.
有很多事情我们想做但是
There are a lot of things we would like to do but
Hay un montón de cosas que nos gustaría hacer pero que
这对我们的团队来说是不可能的，但它确实丰富了我，并且对未来有用。
That is not possible for our team, but it does enrich me and can be useful for the future.
que para nuestro equipo no se puede, pero sí que me enriquece y me puede servir para el futuro.
所以我无法停止寻找、分析。
So I can't stop looking, analyzing.
Entonces no dejo de mirar, de analizar.
并不断观看足球比赛，我从未断开连接。
and constantly watching football, I never disconnect.
y constantemente mirando fútbol, no desconecto nunca.
不，我不需要它。
No, I don't need it.
No, no me hace falta.
我喜欢它并且我需要它。
I like it and I need it.
Me gusta y lo necesito.
当召唤超出等级的玩家时，你更喜欢什么？
What do you favor when calling up a player beyond the level?
¿Qué privilegias al momento de convocar a un jugador más allá del nivel?
例如，我想到了从博卡转会而来的X·费尔南德斯……
I think, for example, of X Fernández, who moved from Boca...
Pienso por ejemplo X Fernández, que pasó de Boca...
沙特阿拉伯还没有在刚刚晋级的球队中首次亮相，但它也有一个重要的旅程以及在奥运会前的经历。
Saudi Arabia has not yet debuted in a team that has just been promoted, but it also has an important journey and what it was in the Pre-Olympic.
Arabia Saudita todavía no debutó en un equipo que recién asciende, pero también tiene un recorrido importante y lo que fue en el Preolímpico.
但我很感兴趣，让我们谈谈标准
but I'm interested, let's say that about the criteria that
pero me interesa digamos eso de los criterios que
一个球员必须会面才能让你征召他加入阿根廷国家队，加入这支两届美国冠军和世界冠军球队。
that a player must meet in order for you to call him up to the Argentine national team, to this two-time American champion and world champion team.
que un jugador debe reunir para que vos lo convoques al seleccionado argentino, a esta selección bicampeona de América y campeona del mundo.
他必须打得好。
It is essential that he plays well.
Es fundamental que juegue bien.
我们现在用我们所拥有的方式就是这样
We now with our oiled way that we have is that
Nosotros ahora con nuestra manera aceitada que tenemos es que
他打得很好，他不会烧球，他知道什么时候必须打球，因为这也是事实
that he plays well, that he does not burn the ball, that he knows when he has to play, because it is also true that
que juegue bien, que no le queme la pelota, que sepa en qué momento tiene que jugar, porque también es verdad que
我们喜欢玩，但我们有门票，不能冒险。
We like to play, but we have our tickets where we cannot risk.
Nos gusta jugar, pero tenemos nuestros tiques donde no podemos arriesgar.
我不喜欢在球场的某个地方丢球。
I don't like losing the ball in a certain part of the court.
no me gusta perder la pelota en cierta parte de la cancha.
这是观察这些人、球队、即将到来的卡斯蒂利亚人、西蒙尼以及所有即将到来的新人的最佳方式。
The best way to see these guys, the team, the Castilian who is coming now, Simeone, all these new guys who are going to come.
La mejor manera de ver a estos chicos, al equi, al castellano que viene ahora, a Simeone, todos estos chicos que van a venir nuevos.
如果你明白我们想要什么，逻辑上在每个位置
If you understand what we want, logically in each position
Si entienden lo que queremos, lógicamente en cada posición
我们有我们的球员，而且我们正在进入。
We have our players and well, we are getting in.
Tenemos nuestros jugadores y bueno, vamos metiendo.
基于我们认为可能缺失的内容。
based on what we think may be missing.
en base a lo que creemos que puede faltar.
但重要的是他必须打得好。
But it is essential that he plays well.
Pero fundamental es que juegue bien.
我们需要这样的球员
We need players who
Necesitamos jugadores que
不要烧掉球并从远处评估它
don't burn the ball and evaluate this from a distance
no le quemen la pelota y evalúas a una distancia esto de
他做出的决定以及他在球场上如何做出这些决定，如果他面临压力，他如何摆脱压力。
the decisions he makes and how he makes them on the court, if he is under pressure, how he gets out of pressing.
las decisiones que toma y cómo las toma dentro de la cancha, si está presionado, cómo sale del pressing.
是的，是的，我告诉你的是，让我们看看媒体的情况，例如，我不是一个从背后接收东西的狂热分子。
yes yes well what I was telling you, let's see in the case of the media, for example, I am not a fanatic who receives things from behind.
sí sí bueno lo que te decía a ver en el caso de los medios por ejemplo a mí yo soy no soy un fanático que reciba de espaldas
很多时候我们会和守门员、中场球员谈论这个问题。
And there are a lot of times that we talk about it with the goalkeepers, we talk about it with those who play as central midfielders.
y hay un montón de veces que con los arqueros lo hablamos, con los que juegan de volante central lo hablamos.
我不喜欢他们从他背后给他的那个球，但我当然不喜欢
I don't like that ball that they give him from his back, but of course I'm not
a mí esa pelota que le dan de espalda no me gusta pero claro yo no soy
一个疯狂的人，我告诉他，看，这是被禁止的，但如果他独自一人，他们可以把它给他，他们可以给第三个拥有中央和
a crazy man that I tell him, look, it's forbidden but if he's alone they can give it to him and they can give a third man with a central and
un loco que le digo mira está prohibido pero si está solo se la pueden dar y pueden dar un tercer hombre con central y
他们这样做，他们让一切变得自然，但他们知道，如果他们在我身后跟着一个人，我不喜欢这样。
They do it, they make it natural but they know that if they come with one behind me, I don't like it.
lo hacen lo hacen natural pero saben que si vienen con uno atrás a mí no me gusta
这样做几乎是被禁止的，因为对我来说似乎没有必要。
It is almost forbidden to do so because it seems unnecessary to me.
que está casi prohibido hacerlo porque me parece innecesario.
在我看来，我们已经采取了那样的逼抢方式，我们已经采取了那样的断球方式。
It seems to me that we have gone to press that way, we have gone to steal balls that way.
Me parece que nosotros hemos ido a presionar de esa manera, hemos ido a robar balones de esa manera.
知道你必须预测并且仅仅预测小费已经是一个目标情况。
Knowing that you have to anticipate and just anticipating the tip is already a goal situation.
Sabiendo que hay que anticiparse y solo con anticipar la puntita ya es situación de gol.
所以这些都是他们已经知道的事情，而那些新来的事情可能还不是。
So those are things that they already know, those who come new, maybe not.
Entonces esas son cosas que ellos ya las saben, los que vienen nuevos, a lo mejor no.
但他们已经知道了这一点，他们知道如果要进行这样的比赛，那是因为中场球员必须完全独自一人。
But they already know it and they know that if that play is made it is because the central midfielder has to be completely alone.
Pero ellos ya lo saben y saben que si se hace esa jugada es porque tiene que estar completamente solo el volante central.
还有其他球队，例如，他所在俱乐部的埃米利亚诺告诉我们，他们不在乎方向盘，因为他们知道他将成为第三人。
and there are other teams, for example, Emiliano in his club tells us that they don't care at the wheel because they know that he is going to be the third man.
y hay otros equipos por ejemplo Emiliano en su club nos cuenta que se la dan igual al volante porque saben que va a ser tercer hombre
我不喜欢这样做，因为如果那个向你施加压力的人从你那里偷走了它，或者因为他已经意识到了这一点。
I am not a fan of that, because if the person who is going to pressure you steals it from you or because he is already aware of that.
Yo no soy fanático de eso, porque si el que te va a presionar te la roba o porque ya está pendiente de eso.
可能会发生。
can happen.
puede pasar.
所以它们是很好的事情，作为教练，每个人都有自己的理解、相信和想要的方式。
So they are things that well, as coaches everyone has their own way of understanding and believing and wanting.
Entonces son cosas que bueno, como entrenadores cada uno tiene su manera de entender y creo y quiero.
让我的球员知道这一点。
Let my players know it.
que mis jugadores la sepan.
你提到了埃米利亚诺·阿迪布。
You mentioned Emiliano Adibu.
Mencionaste a Emiliano Adibu.
您是否计划在 2021 年将其超越阿玛尼的新冠疫情？
Were you planning to put it beyond Armani's COVID in 2021?
¿Tenías pensado ponerlo más allá del COVID de Armani en 2021?
是的。
Yeah.
Sí.
是的，这对我来说并不难。
Yes, it's not hard for me to say.
Sí, no me cuesta decirlo.
佛朗哥非常好。
Franco was very good.
Franco estaba muy bien.
他给了我们很多东西，埃米利亚诺也在不断推动。
He had given us a lot of things and Emiliano came pushing.
nos había dado un montón de cosas y Emiliano vino empujando.
非常好，我想这也许不是因为他
very good and I think it was a matter of maybe if it wasn't because of him
muy bien y yo creo que era cuestión de que a lo mejor si no fue por él
如果是因为新冠疫情，我们会在比赛期间的某个时候给他机会，因为他已经得到了很多机会。
Had it been due to COVID, at some point during the tournament we would have given him the opportunity as he had been given plenty.
hubiera sido por el COVID, en algún momento del torneo le hubiéramos dado la oportunidad como se le había dado un montón.
这些都是正在发生的事情。
These are things that happen.
Son cosas que pasan.
他必须在那里比赛。
He had to play there.
le tocó jugar ahí.
我们总是轮到球员上场并且表现出色。
We always have a player's turn to play and do well.
Nosotros siempre que a un jugador le toque jugar y le va bien.
并让我们没有理由离开。
and gives us no reason to leave.
y no nos da razones para salir.
他留在那里，然后发生的一切都是他赚来的。
He stayed there and then everything that happened was earned by him.
Ahí ha quedado y después todo lo que ha pasado se lo ha ganado él.
除了我们所看到和了解的关于埃米利亚诺、迪布的一切之外，
Beyond everything we saw and know about Emiliano, Dibu,
Más allá de todo lo que nosotros vimos y conocemos de Emiliano, de Dibu,
您每天看到的有什么东西比其他人看到的更让您惊讶或更多？
Is there anything that you see on a daily basis that surprises you as much or more than what everyone else sees?
¿Hay algo que vos veas en el día a día que te sorprenda tanto o más que lo que todo el mundo ve?
你知道画画吗？
Do you know about Draw?
conoce de Dibu?
好吧，我想我知道它是什么样子，但它没有......
Well I think I know what it looks like, it doesn't have...
Bueno yo creo que sé lo que se ve, no tiene...
后面还有一个……是他，是他，是一个……的家伙。
Behind that there is another... It's him, that's him, it's a guy who...
atrás de eso hay otra... Es él, es ese es él, es un tipo que...
散发出自信，总是积极的，尽管
radiates confidence, is always positive, although
irradia confianza, está siempre positivo, aunque
可能不对，即使发送了也没有显示给你。
It may not be right, it doesn't show it to you even if it has been sent.
pueda no estar bien no te lo demuestra aunque se haya mandado
或者犯了错误，他继续热情地给予，继续传播，我认为
or has had a mistake, he continues to give with enthusiasm, continues to transmit that and I think that
o haya tenido un error, él sigue dando con ganas, sigue transmitiendo eso y creo que
对于一支球队来说，拥有一名具备这种能力的门将是至关重要的
It is essential for a team to have a goalkeeper who has that
es fundamental para un equipo tener un arquero que tiene esa
这种愿望是根本性的。
That desire is fundamental.
Esas ganas son fundamentales.
他是一个散发着自信的男孩。
He is a boy who radiates confidence.
Es un chico que irradia confianza.
他在任何时候都不会向你传达我们所有人都有的疑虑，他不会向你传达这些疑虑。
And at no time does he convey to you the doubts that we all have, he does not convey them to you.
Y no en ningún momento te transmite las dudas que todo el mundo las tenemos, él no te las transmite.
伊玛利亚（Imaria）是否有一篇帖子讲述了当利奥（Leo）停止比赛时会发生什么？
Is there a post from Imaria about what will happen at some point when Leo stops playing?
¿Hay un post de Imaría como en algún momento va a pasar cuando deje de jugar Leo?
你认为球队需要习惯缺席还是忍受严重犯规？
Do you think the team needs to get used to an absence or live with a major foul?
¿Crees que el equipo necesita acostumbrarse a una ausencia o convivir con una falta importante?
从逻辑上讲不是。
Logically not.
Lógico que no.
它是不可替代的。
It is irreplaceable.
Es irreemplazable.
他们不是可以被取代的球员。
They are not players who can be replaced.
No son jugadores que se pueden reemplazar.
不可能的。
Impossible.
Imposible.
连机会都没有了。
There's not even a chance.
No hay ni una chance.
Fideo 和 Leo 都是独一无二的玩家。
They are unique players, both Fideo and Leo.
Son jugadores únicos, tanto Fideo como Leo.
就 Fideo 而言，他不会再来了。
In the case of Fideo, he is not going to come anymore.
En el caso de Fideo, que ya no va a venir más.
他已经说过了，我们不会试图寻找替代者，因为这将是一个错误，寻找那个球员将是一个错误
and he has said it, we will not try to find a replacement, because it would be a mistake, it would be a mistake to look for the player who
y lo ha dicho, no intentaremos buscar un reemplazante, porque sería un error, sería un error buscar el jugador que
和他做同样事情的人，不存在。
that does the same as him, does not exist.
que haga lo mismo que él, no existe.
确实，他给我们带来了左右两侧的宽度，尤其是在我们踢右侧的情况下
It's true that what he gave us was width both on the right and on the left, much more with us playing on the right
verdad que lo que él nos daba era amplitud tanto por derecha como por izquierda bastante más con nosotros jugado por derecha
我们将努力寻找一名能够做出贡献的球员，我认为我们队中有他
We will try to find a player who can, and I think we have him in the team, who can contribute that
intentaremos buscar a un jugador que pueda, y creo que lo tenemos en el equipo, que pueda aportar eso
这是广度，但是是一对一的，理解比赛，摆脱比赛。
It's breadth, but then one on one, understanding the play, getting out of the game.
Es amplitud, pero después el uno contra uno, el entender la jugada, el sacarse de la galera jugada.
不可思议，只有他有。
incredible, only he had it.
increíble, sólo lo tenía él.
所以团队必须
So the team will have to
Así que el equipo tendrá que
我不是说重置，但是……
I'm not saying reset, but yes...
No digo de resetearse, pero sí...
为什么不尝试以不同的方式打球，因为他不在场呢？
Why not try to play differently because he's not there?
¿Por qué no intentar jugar de otra manera porque no esté él?
当时你是怎么处理的？
How did you manage at the time?
¿Cómo en su momento gestionaste
他出现在安赫尔的广播中，要求他们在美洲杯比赛结束后给他打电话，他在美洲杯上首发并被替换下场。
He appeared on Ángel's radio requesting that they call him after what had been that Copa América in which he started as a starter and was replaced
apareció en la de Ángel pidiendo por radio que lo llamaran después de lo que había sido esa Copa América en la que empezó como titular fue reemplazado
后来它在某个时候被使用，例如当它通过阿萨门迪亚进入巴拉圭时。
Later it was used at some point, such as when it entered with Paraguay through Arsamendia.
Después fue utilizado en algún momento, como por ejemplo cuando entró con Paraguay por Arsamendia.
标记阿萨门迪亚，然后重新出现。
to mark Arsamendia and then reappears.
para marcar a Arsamendia y después reaparece.
要求打电话，当他拒绝时，对我的朋友他说不，我会喜欢的......
asking for a call, when he says no, to my friends he says no, I would have liked it...
pidiendo una convocatoria, cuando él dice no, a mis amigos me dice no, me hubiera gustado que...
你为什么不留在法国？
Why don't you stay in France?
¿Por qué no te quedas en Francia?
不，我想我搞砸了数百万阿根廷人。
No, I think I screwed millions of Argentines.
No, yo creo que me puté en millones de argentinos.
这封信是给你的。
The message was for you.
El mensaje era para vos.
你是怎么做到的？
How did you manage it?
¿Cómo lo gestionaste?
除了认识他之外，我还知道他是一个...
Apart from knowing him, I know that he is a kid who...
Yo aparte de conocerlo, sé que es un pibe que...
他渴望加入国家队，他已经证明了这一点。
He was dying to be in the national team, he has shown it.
Se moría de ganas por estar en la selección, lo ha demostrado.
但当时我们非常关心给尼科·冈萨雷斯上场的机会。
But at that moment we were very concerned about giving Nico González the opportunity to play.
Pero nosotros en ese momento estábamos muy pendientes de dar la posibilidad de jugar a Nico González.
我们相信他...
that we believed that he...
que creíamos que él...
那个男孩可以给我们带来很多，并把他和安赫尔一起带来，我们相信他不会
that the boy could give us a lot and bring him along with Ángel, we believed that he would not
que el chico nos podía dar un montón y traerlo junto a Ángel creíamos que no
我们可以给他他需要的时间。
We could give him the minutes he needed.
le podíamos dar los minutos que necesitaba.
好吧，我给他打了电话，在他在电视上讲话之后我给他打了电话，我想我……
And well, I called him, I called him after that talk he had on television, I think I...
Y bueno, yo lo llamé, lo llamé después de esa charla que él tuvo en la televisión, creo que lo...
小第二。
Little second.
Poco segundo.
你对他说了些什么吗？
Did you say something to him?
¿Le dijiste algo?
是的，不，如果我们离开了，那就已经在一起了。
Yes, no, if we left it was already together.
Sí, no, si nos largamos ya era junto.
因为他告诉我，我哭着说我想去那里，我也和他一起哭，我说，如果你要去那里，没有人告诉你你不会在那里。
because he told me, I was crying that I wanted to be there and I was also crying with him and I said, if you're going to be there, no one told you that you're not going to be there.
porque él me dijo, yo lloraba que quería estar y yo también lloraba con él y dije, si vas a estar, nadie te dijo que no vas a estar.
问题是现在我不需要你在场。
The problem is that now I don't need you to be there.
El problema es que ahora yo no necesito que estés.
你不是来给尼科·冈萨雷斯机会的，卢卡斯·奥坎波也和我们一起来，球员们
that you are not here to give Nico González the chance, Lucas Ocampo was also coming with us, players who
que no estés para dar la posibilidad a Nico González, estaba Lucas Ocampo también viniendo con nosotros, jugadores que
如果迪玛利亚处于阴影之中，我不知道他们是否会
having Di María in the shadows, I don't know if they would have been
tener en la sombra a Di María, no sé si hubieran estado
考虑到他们当时所能给予的。
given what they could give at that time.
dado lo que podían dar en ese momento.
好吧，在任何情况下都没有不带他回来的想法，他会安全的。
Well, under no circumstances was the idea of ​​not bringing him back, he was going to be safe.
Bueno, bajo ningún concepto la idea era no traerlo más, él iba a estar seguro.
但是，是的，对于他来说，也许如果我们要……
but yes, for him, maybe if we are going to...
pero sí que para él a lo mejor si vamos a...
对于希拉尔·菲诺来说，也许站在他这边，我也可能是一样的，如果事实是他是一个可爱又可爱的男孩的话。
To Hilar Fino, perhaps on his side, I could be the same, if the truth is that he is a boy who is endearing and
A Hilar Fino a lo mejor de su lado decía yo podía estar igual si es la verdad que es un chico que es entrañable y estar
对于他和整个团队来说，这本来就是一个团队。
in a group for him and for the entire group it would have been.
en un grupo para para él y para todo el grupo hubiera sido.
更好，但对于在他的位置上踢球或取代他的球员来说......
better, but for the player who plays in his position or who is replacing him...
mejor, pero para el jugador que juega en su posición o que está reemplazando a él...
这是非常勇敢的，但这些是我们之前讨论过的事情。
It's very brave, but these are things we were talking about before.
Es muy bravo, pero son cosas de lo que hablábamos antes.
玩家很难理解这一点。
It is difficult for the player to understand that.
Que el jugador es difícil que entienda eso.
幸运的是，豪尔赫想去那里。
Jorge wants to be there, luckily.
Jorge quiere estar, por suerte.
他明白这一点，尽管从逻辑上讲，这一刻很难。
He understood it, although logically at that moment it was hard.
Él lo entendió, aunque lógicamente en ese momento era duro.
但我认为发生的一切对球队和国家队来说都是积极的，因为那些孩子
but I think that everything that happened was positive for the group and the national team because those kids
pero creo que para el grupo y para la selección fue positivo todo lo que se dio porque esos chicos
在对手中踢球的人采取了我们需要的步骤。
who played in their opposition took that step that we needed.
que jugaban en su oposición dieron ese paso que nosotros necesitábamos.
当世界杯结束，阿根廷获胜，在 Dsports 上聊天时，我想要
When the World Cup ends and Argentina wins, chatting on Dsports, I wanted
Cuando termina el Mundial y gana Argentina, charlando por Dsports, yo quería
我想知道你为什么把时间调到 11，然后你告诉我 Cundé 的事，他倾向于倒闭。
to know why you had turned it to 11 and then you told me about Cundé who tended to close down.
saber por qué la habías puesto de 11 y ahí me contaste lo de Cundé que tendía a cerrarse.
你是如何做出决定的？
How did you make the decision?
¿Cómo tomaste la decisión?
不仅要包括它，而且要包括在那里。
Not just to include it, but to include it there.
No solo de incluirlo, sino de incluirlo ahí.
你单独拿了它，你要把它放在右边，然后你就改变了。
You took it alone, you were going to put it on the right and you changed.
La tomaste solo, lo ibas a poner por la derecha y cambiaste.
告诉我一些那是什么样子的。
Tell me a little about what that was like.
Contame un poco cómo fue eso.
有点奇怪。
It's a little strange.
Es un poco extraña.
因为我直到比赛当天中午才告诉教练组。
because I didn't tell the coaching staff until the day of the game, at noon.
porque yo al cuerpo técnico no se la dije hasta el día del partido, al mediodía.
我脑子里有这个想法，我就在身边，我们谈论了如何
I had it in my head, I was around and we talked all about how
yo la tenia en la cabeza, rondaba y hablabamos todo de como
进攻，我很清楚我们必须从那边进攻
attack and I was very clear that we had to attack from that side and
atacar y yo tenía clarísimo que nosotros teníamos que atacar por aquel lado y
和整个教练组一起走过大学，我告诉他们我们要和......
and walking through the university with the entire coaching staff I tell them we are going to play with...
y caminando por la universidad con todo el cuerpo técnico les digo vamos a jugar con...
天使在左边，在塔利亚菲科后面。
Angel on the left and behind Tagliafico.
Ángel a la izquierda y atrás Tagliafico.
好吧，一如既往，没有人反对我，因为当他们看到我这样的时候。
Well, as always, no one opposes me because when they see me like this.
Bueno, como siempre, ninguno me da la contra porque cuando me ven así.
好吧，巴勃罗告诉我，我喜欢它，我喜欢它，疯狂，我喜欢它。
And well, Pablo tells me, I like it, I like it, crazy, I like it.
Y bueno, Pablo me dice, me gusta, me gusta, loco, me gusta.
我只需要一点点推动。
And I just needed that little push.
Y yo necesitaba solo ese empujoncito.
但我确实说过，在看到法国之后的一周，我分析了我们是多么遗憾
but i did say that the week after seeing france analyze how sorry i was that we
pero yo sí que la semana después de ver a francia analizar lo sentía de que nosotros
很多事情，不仅是安赫尔的版本，在右路他们还用姆巴佩进攻，我们需要罗德里戈。
Many things, not only the edition of Ángel, on the right they also attacked with Mbappé, we needed to have Rodrigo.
Muchas cosas, no solo la edición de Ángel, por derecha también ellos atacaban con Mbappé, necesitábamos tener a Rodrigo.
请帮助我们处理 UEL。
Give us a hand with the UEL.
que nos dé una mano con la UEL.
所以他关闭了很多事情。
So he was closing a lot of things.
Entonces fue cerrando un montón de cosas.
但最重要的是我们和亚历克西斯在中间
but the fundamental thing was that we were out there with Alexis in the middle
pero lo fundamental era que nosotros por ahí con Alexis en la entrelinia
会担心孔德，而登贝莱不会下去跟随他
was going to worry Koundé and Dembelé was not going to go down to follow him
iba a preocupar a Koundé y Dembelé no iba a bajar para seguirlo a
费迪奥和如果登贝莱进攻塔利亚菲科，我们注意到他善于遏制他。
Fideo and if Dembélé attacked, Thaliafico, we noticed that he was good at containing him.
a Fideo y si atacaba Dembélé, Thaliafico, notábamos que estaba bien para contenerlo.
这是一个经过深思熟虑的决定，但我们甚至没有告诉球员。
It was a well-thought-out decision but we didn't even tell it to the players.
Fue una decisión bastante pensada pero que no se la dijimos ni a los jugadores.
在这种情况下，我，教练组，在演讲前几个小时也没有这样做，因为我需要
nor in this case did I, the coaching staff, a couple of hours before giving the talk because I needed
ni yo en este caso cuerpo técnico un par de horas antes de dar la charla porque yo necesitaba
说服自己，然后不要怀疑，因为现在不是怀疑的时候。
convince myself and then let there be no doubt because it was not a time to have a doubt.
convencerme a mí mismo y después que no haya ninguna duda porque no era un momento de tener una duda.
好吧，结果很好。
And well, it turned out well.
Y bueno, salió bien.
有时。
And there are times when.
Y hay momentos en los que.
你的同事认识你并且说不，不。
Your staff colleagues know you and say no, no.
tus compañeros de staff te conocen y te dicen no, no.
我不和你争论，我不提出反驳，因为我认为这是非常清楚的。
I am not arguing with you, I am not proposing a counterargument because I see it as very clear.
No te discuto, no te planteo un contraargumento porque lo veo muy definido.
此外，他们是在声乐足球场周围出生的人。
Besides, they are guys who were born around a vocal soccer field.
Aparte que son tipos que nacieron alrededor de una cancha de fútbol de voz.
当你周五和周一比赛的时候，你可以讨论这个问题。
When you play on Friday and Monday you can discuss it.
Cuando jugás un viernes y el lunes sí te la puedes discutir.
你辩论它，你说，不，但是你看，你为什么不考虑一下这个？
You debate it, you say, no, but look, why don't you think about this?
Te la discutes, dices, no, pero mirá, ¿y por qué no pensas en este?
看这里。
Look here.
Mirá acá.
比赛前你有四天的时间，但是当你在比赛当天，即使其中之一说
You have four days before the game, but when you are on the day of the game, even if one of them says
tenés cuatro días al partido, pero cuando estás en el día del partido, aunque uno de ellos diga
不，我们给吧。
No, let's give it.
No, vamos a darle.
信心更好，对什么事情下定决心更好
Confidence is better, it is better to be totally determined about what
Es mejor la confianza, es mejor estar totalmente decidido a lo que
来表达你想要表达的某种疑问。
to what you want to convey a certain doubt.
a lo que querés a transmitir una cierta duda.
所以你已经认识我了。
So you already know me.
Entonces eso ya me conocen.
他们意识到我对此深信不疑，并且这是我可以很好地向团队传达的信息。
And they realized that I was convinced of that and that it was what I could convey well to the team.
Y se dieron cuenta de que yo estaba convencido con eso y que era lo que podía transmitirle al equipo bien.
因为我告诉你们的这四五件事中有很多事情都结束了。
because there were many things of these four or five that I told you that all closed.
porque había muchas cosas de estas cuatro o cinco que te dije que cerraban todas.
所以很难不同意。
So it was hard to disagree.
Entonces era difícil no estar de acuerdo.
巴勃罗，教练组的每位成员对你有何贡献？
What does each member of the coaching staff contribute to you, Pablo?
¿Qué te aporta cada integrante del cuerpo técnico, Pablo?
埃尔·拉通、沃尔特、马蒂亚斯、马纳、马丁、托卡利。
El Ratón, Walter, Matías, Mana, Martín, Tocali.
每一个给你什么？
What does each one give you?
¿Qué te da cada uno?
最主要的是，在职业足球中谈论这个似乎很奇怪。
The main thing is that it seems strange to talk about this in professional football.
Lo principal es que parece raro hablar de esto en el fútbol profesional.
选拔高水平就是好人
a selection of high levels is good people
una selección de altos niveles es buena gente
当你和优秀的人一起工作时，这是非常困难的。
When you work with good people it is very difficult, very difficult.
Cuando vos trabajas con buena gente es muy difícil, muy difícil.
嗯，进球，球进还是没进，那是次要的。
Well, the goal, the ball goes in or it doesn't go in, that is secondary.
Pues el gol, la pelota entra o no entra, eso es secundario.
在很多方面，但他们都是好人，他们是
in a lot of ways, but they are good people, they are
en un montón de aspectos, pero que son buena gente, que son
想要为自己和团队提供最好的帮助的人。
people who want the best for themselves and for the team.
gente que quiere lo mejor para uno mismo y para la selección.
然后每个人都有自己的事情。
And then everyone has their own thing.
Y después cada uno tiene lo suyo.
巴勃罗是那个...
Pablo is the guy who...
Pablo es el tipo que...
他看到里面的东西说不，但如果你看一下个人资料，如果它看起来是这样，那对我们来说更好。
He sees things inside that say no, but if you look at the profile, if it looks this way, it is better for us.
ve cosas adentro que dice no pero si fijate el perfil si se perfila para este lado nosotros es mejor para
对我们来说，这里有恩佐指挥它
For us, here we have Enzo who does command it
para nosotros, acá tenemos a Enzo que si lo manda
尼科一对一，他传球很好，有时我们会换人。
Nico goes one on one, he has a good pass, sometimes we change.
a Nico se mete uno contra uno, tiene buen pase, hay veces cambiamos.
对于亚历克西斯来说，这些都是他在那些环境中移动过并且熟悉的东西。
with Alexis, these are things that he has moved in those environments and are familiar with.
con Alexis, son cosas que él se ha movido en esos ambientes y es familiar.
“老鼠”是在正确的时间出现的正确的词。他是我在国家队时担任队长的人，当他说话时，他没有举手。
The mouse is the right word at the right time. He is a guy who was captain when I was in the national team and when he spoke he didn't fly a hand.
el ratón es la palabra justa en el momento justo es un tipo que era capitán cuando yo estaba en la selección y cuando hablaba él no volaba una mano
飞翔，尤其是因为他所传达的严肃性，因为他是一个叛逆的家伙。
fly, especially because of the seriousness he conveys, because he is a rebellious guy.
mosca, sobre todo por la seriedad que transmite, porque es un tipo recontra
非常有礼貌，非常有礼貌，他说话的时候...
very polite, very polite, where when he speaks...
muy educado, muy educado, donde cuando habla...
他说话发自内心，而且非常有礼貌。
He speaks from the heart and very polite.
habla desde el corazón y muy educado.
他还负责与沃尔特一起停球。
He is also in charge of stopping the ball with Walter.
Se encarga también con la pelota parada con Walter.
沃尔特除了是终生的朋友之外，还一起训练多年，
And Walter, in addition to being a lifelong friend, who would train for years together,
Y Walter, además de ser amigo de toda la vida, que íbamos a entrenar años juntos,
这是这群人中最严肃的一个，看起来很……
It is the serious one of the group who seems to be very...
Es el serio del grupo el que parece que es muy...
非常安静，但有着无可挑剔的记录。
very quiet, but has an impeccable track record.
muy callado, pero tiene una trayectoria intachable.
在意大利，他学到了很多东西，也有教练组。
In Italy, where he has learned a lot, there has been a coaching staff.
en Italia, donde ha aprendido un montón, ha estado un cuerpo técnico.
在战术层面上它给了我们很多，在防守层面上它给了我们很多。
And at a tactical level it gives us a lot, at a defensive level it gives us a lot.
Y a nivel táctico nos da un montón, a nivel defensivo nos da un montón.
你的想法是，在你标记的区域，你不看球，你必须触碰球员......
What you think is that in the area you mark and you don't look at the ball, you have to touch the player...
de lo que piensa que en el área se marca y no se mira la pelota, hay que tocar al jugador...
这些是他告诉球员并让他们铭记在心的事情。
These are things that he tells the players and that sticks with them.
Son cosas que les va diciendo a los jugadores y que se les va quedando.
每当有新人到来时，Yegua 对我说的第一句话，因为他叫我 Yegua，他告诉我 Yegua，我们必须......
And every time a new one comes, the first thing that Yegua says to me, because he calls me Yegua, he tells me Yegua, we have to...
Y cada vez que viene uno nuevo, lo primero que me dice Yegua, porque a mí me dice Yegua, me dice Yegua, tenemos que...
和这个人谈谈。
Talk to this one.
Hablar con este.
我能问一下为什么他们说需要你吗？
Can I ask why they say it takes you?
¿Puedo preguntar por qué te dicen lleva?
不，因为当我小的时候我会跑，我是一头动物，一匹马。
No, because when I was little I ran, I was an animal, a horse.
No, porque yo de chiquito corría, era un animal, un caballo.
而不是马，马。
Instead of Horse, Mare.
En vez de Caballo, Yegua.
当然，我跑到了那里，这个绰号就一直留在我身上。
Of course, I ran there, that nickname stuck to me.
Claro, corrí ahí, me quedó ese apodo.
耶瓜告诉我，我们必须在防守上下功夫。
And Yegua tells me, we have to work on defense.
Y me dice Yegua, hay que trabajar lo defensivo.
因此玩家已经被标记了。
and thus the player is already marked.
y así al jugador ya le queda marcado.
而马蒂，马蒂马纳绝对是分析一切的人。
And Mati, Mati Mana is the one who analyzes absolutely everything.
Y Mati, Mati Mana es el que analiza absolutamente todo.
幸运的是，他学会了过滤我们，因为他当然热爱足球，热爱......
Luckily he learned to filter us because of course he is in love with football, a lover of...
Aprendió por suerte a filtrarnos porque claro él es un enamorado del fútbol, un enamorado de...
组合传球，通过球压制对手。
to put together passes, to subdue the rival through the ball.
de juntar pases, de someter al rival a través de la pelota.
有时他会给我们提供信息，幸运的是他了解我们的比赛方式。
And there are times when he gives us information and luckily he has understood our way of playing.
Y hay veces que nos pasa información y por suerte él ha entendido nuestra manera de jugar.
他是一个出色的人，但对我们来说这又是有效的。
He is a crack as a person and for us it is valid again.
es un crack como persona y que para nosotros es recontra válido.
以及几位老师的职位，除了担任老师之外
and several posts to the teacher who, in addition to being a teacher
y varias puestas al profe que además de ser un profe
我总是说我对身体准备不是那么感兴趣，而是对我感兴趣的事情感兴趣。
I always say that I'm not so interested in physical preparation, but rather what interests me.
que yo siempre digo que a mí no es que me interese tanto la preparación física, sino lo que me interesa es.
玩家理解为什么要做这些事情，如果有时不需要参加比赛，那么事情就没有完成，幸运的是他
that the player understands why things are done and if there are times when there is no need to do a race it is not done and luckily he
que el jugador entienda por qué se hacen las cosas y si hay veces que no hay que hacer una carrera no se hace y él por suerte
他比任何人都更了解这一点，他是一个好人，每个人都爱他，对我们来说这是根本。
He understands it better than anyone, he is a good guy, everyone loves him and for us that is fundamental.
Lo entiende mejor que nadie, es un buen tipo, lo quieren todos y para nosotros eso es fundamental.
马丁痴迷于工作，而不是徒劳地实现工作所取得的一切。
and Martín is obsessed with work, not in vain everything that has been achieved with it.
y Martín es un obsesionado del trabajo, no en vano todo lo que se ha conseguido con él.
埃米利亚诺、弗朗哥和那些一直在阻止它的人，它已经实现了。
Emiliano, with Franco, with the guys who have been stopping it, it has been achieved.
Emiliano, con Franco, con los chicos que han estado atajando se ha conseguido.
他工作很多，他一直在那里。
He works a lot, he is constantly there.
él trabaja muchísimo, está constantemente.
我们总是告诉他，他花了很多时间在计算机分析上。
We always tell him that he spends so much time on the computer analyzing.
Nosotros siempre le decimos que hace tanto tiempo en la computadora analizando.
请注意，射箭职业已经进步了很多，给了我们很大的帮助。
Notice that the archery profession has improved a lot and has given us a big hand.
Fíjate que la profesión de arquero ha mejorado un montón y nos ha dado una mano grande.
我们对每个人都很满意。
We are very happy with everyone.
Estamos muy contentos de todos.
嗯，鼠标 Allara 是我们 2018 年 Dsports 的合作伙伴，他告诉我
Well, the mouse Allara was our partner at Dsports in 2018 and he told me
Pues es que el ratón Allara fue compañero nuestro en Dsports en 2018 y me dijo
中后卫必须赢得决斗，这一点一直困扰着我。
A center back has to win duels and it stuck with me.
un central tiene que ganar duelos y me quedó grabado.
这句话就像一个咒语，不仅仅是通过吃那个蛋糕来把它清理干净
of that phrase and it is like a mantra beyond getting it clean from having that cake
de esa frase y es como un mantra más allá de sacarla limpia de tener ese pastel
库蒂放入的烘干机类型，库蒂赢得决斗，利桑德罗赢得决斗，就是这样。
type of dryer that Cuti puts in, Cuti wins duels, Lisandro wins duels and that's the thing.
tipo secador que mete Cuti, Cuti gana duelos, Lisandro gana duelos y ahí está la cuestión.
你如何处理成功的后果？
How do you deal with the repercussions of success?
¿Cómo te llevas con las repercusiones del éxito?
我的意思是，你为银行、航空公司拍过广告，做过演讲，比如简介……
I mean, you've done commercials for banks, airlines, you give talks, there's like a profile...
O sea, has hecho comerciales para bancos, aerolíneas, das charlas, hay como un perfil...
这不可避免地来自于随阿根廷队获得世界冠军和两届美国冠军。
which inevitably comes from having been world champion and two-time American champion with Argentina.
que inevitablemente genera haber sido campeón del mundo y bicampeón de América con Argentina.
你如何管理它？
How do you manage it?
¿Cómo lo gestionas vos?
你喜欢它？
Do you like it?
¿Te gusta?
你喜欢吗？
Do you enjoy it?
¿Lo disfrutás?
对你来说很难吗？
Is it difficult for you?
¿Te cuesta?
不，好吧，我顺其自然，这不花钱，我不喜欢它，我不喜欢它，我顺其自然。
No, well, I take it naturally, it doesn't cost me, I don't like it, I don't like it, I take it naturally.
No, bueno, lo tomo natural, ni me cuesta, ni me gusta, ni me gusta, lo tomo natural.
我们正在经历的那一刻，是积极的。
of the moment we are going through, positive.
del momento que estamos atravesando, positivo.
知道在某些时候它会出错，因为它不会总是这样，如果它确实出错了，我们也会以同样的方式
knowing that at some point it will go wrong because it will not always be like this and if it does go wrong we will be in the same way
sabiendo que en algún momento se va a torcer porque no va a ser siempre así y si se tuerce estaremos de la misma manera
有一个平衡，但我想要的最重要的事情
with a balance but the most important thing that I want
con un equilibrio pero lo más importante que yo quiero que
让这一切都得到拯救。
let all this be rescued.
que se rescate todo esto.
如果我们这样做并这样说话。
If we do all this and talk this way.
Si hacemos todo esto y hablamos de esta manera.
我们让它变得自然，我们所做的许多事情都不需要花费我们任何成本
We make it natural, it costs us nothing and many of the things we do
Lo hacemos natural, no nos cuesta nada y muchas de las cosas que hacemos
我们希望以他们为榜样，特别是因为
We would like them to be taken as an example, especially because
Nos gustaría que se tomen de ejemplo, sobre todo porque
因为这就是他们灌输给我们的。
because that's what they instilled in us.
porque es lo que nos inculcaron a nosotros.
我们是在青年队中长大的。
We grew up in the youth team.
Nosotros nos criamos en la selección juvenil.
以这种方式理解足球，尊重你的队友，尊重你的对手。
with this way of understanding football, with respect for your teammate, respect for your rival.
con esta manera de entender el fútbol, con el respeto al compañero, el respeto al rival.
我们知道我们在任何方面都不是最好的，但我们可以做得非常好，即使我们没有获胜，我们也不是最差的。
knowing that we are not the best at anything, but that we can be very good and that when we don't win we are not the worst.
sabiendo de que no somos los mejores en nada, pero que podemos ser muy buenos y que cuando no se gana no somos los peores.
我认为所有这些都是我们希望每个人都能理解的信息。
all those things that I think is a message that we would like everyone to assimilate.
todas esas cosas que creo que es un mensaje que nos gustaría que todo el mundo lo asimile.
但这对我来说并不困难，我不会开始思考他们曾经如何每天问我
but it's not difficult for me, I don't start thinking about how they once asked me every day
pero no me cuesta, no me pongo a pensar como una vez me preguntaron todos los días
如果你早上起床，我就是世界冠军，我不是不，因为事情不是那样的，生活还要继续。
If you get up in the morning I am a world champion and I am no no because because it is not like that, life goes on.
si te levantas a la mañana soy campeón del mundo y soy que no no porque porque no es así la vida sigue
但有时你会坐下来享受这段旅程。
But there are times when you sit back and enjoy the ride.
Pero hay momentos en los que te sentás y disfrutás del viaje.
更多关于停留、成功、旅程的信息。
more about the stops, the successes, the journey.
más sea de las paradas, de los éxitos, del recorrido.
好吧，当我们在这里、此时此刻，我们很享受它。
Well, we enjoy it when we are here, in the moment.
Bueno, lo disfrutamos cuando estamos acá, en el momento.
我的意思是，当时我们和教练组相处得很好，我们很享受......
I mean, at the time we were fine with the coaching staff, we enjoyed...
O sea, en el momento estábamos bien con el cuerpo técnico, disfrutamos...
比赛的时刻到来了，我们也一样。
And the moment of the game arrives and we are the same.
Y llega el momento del partido y estamos igual.
如果我们在印度尼西亚对阵印度尼西亚或者我们参加决赛，这是真的
and this is real if we play against indonesia in indonesia or we play the final of
y esto es real si jugamos contra indonesia en indonesia o jugamos la final de
对于美洲杯，我们理解这场比赛的方式是一样的。
of the Copa América, our way of understanding that match is the same.
de la Copa América, nuestra manera de entender ese partido es el mismo.
我们总是对比赛感到焦虑，因为穿着这件球衣踢球意义重大，因为我们感受到了这一点。
We are always anxious about the game because it means a lot to play with this shirt and because we feel it.
Siempre estamos con la ansiedad del partido porque representa mucho jugar con esta camiseta y porque nos sentimos.
各方必须平等对待。
that all parties must be taken equally.
de que hay que tomar todos los partidos igual.
从那里开始，我相信
From there, I believe that
A partir de ahí, yo creo que
我们不会对我们已经赢得的一切或即将到来的一切施加压力，因为否则最终
We do not put the pressure of everything we have won or everything that is coming because otherwise in the end
no nos metemos la presión de todo lo que hemos ganado o todo lo que viene porque sino al final
你不享受。
You don't enjoy.
No disfrutás.
我们尝试以自己的方式享受它。
We try to enjoy it in our own way.
Nosotros intentamos disfrutar a nuestra manera.
当阿根廷队在马拉卡纳凭借尼科的进球击败他们时，你会说，好吧，我必须看看我是否有足够的精力。
When Argentina beats them at the Maracaná with Nico's goal and you say, well, I have to see if I have all the energy.
Cuando Argentina le gana en el Maracaná con el gol de Nico y vos decís, bueno, yo hay que ver si tengo todas las energías.
显然，这最终与成就本身一样重要，甚至更重要，是一项重要的成就。
Obviously that ended up being as important or more important than the achievement itself, an important achievement.
Obviamente terminó eso siendo tan o más importante que el logro en sí, un logro importante.
我真的理解你为什么这么说，我认为这与。
I really understood why you said what you said and I think it had to do with.
Yo entendí realmente por qué habías dicho lo que dijiste y creo que tenía que ver con.
事实是，这一切，有时让我不知所措，因为我也有生活，我的父母，我的妻子，我的孩子。
The truth is that all this, there are moments when it overwhelms me, because I also have a life, my parents, my wife, my children.
La verdad que todo esto, hay momentos en los que me abruma, porque además tengo una vida, mis viejos, mi mujer, mis hijos.
现在，从远处看，您觉得自己如何处理这种情况？
Now from a distance, how do you feel you handled that situation?
¿Cómo ahora a la distancia, cómo sentís que manejaste esa situación?
嗯，我很自然地走到一边，因为我不得不说。
Well, naturally I went aside because I had to say it.
Bueno, natural iba aparte porque lo tenía que decir.
我度过了非常糟糕的一年。
I have had an ugly, ugly year.
Yo he llevado un año feo, feo.
丑陋，你明白，不，我不喜欢它。
Ugly, you understand, no, I wasn't enjoying it.
feo a ese entiende, no, no lo estaba disfrutando.
已经有六场非常非常非常艰难的淘汰赛了。
There have been six very tough, very tough eliminatory parties.
Habían pasado seis partidos eliminatorios durísimos, durísimo.
其中我们不...
in which we do not...
en los cuales nosotros no...
我从个人角度来说，这不好。
I speak on a personal level, it was not good.
Hablo a nivel personal, no estaba bien.
他经历过困难时期。
He had gone through difficult times.
Había pasado momentos difíciles.
想到很多事情，我也需要
a lot of things come to mind, I also needed
se te viene un montón de cosas a la cabeza, necesitaba también
我告诉你的，与球员讨论，与我的家人讨论，与主教练讨论，评论我的感受，采取行动
what I told you, talk about it with the players, talk about it with my family, talk about it with the managers, comment on what I felt, take a
esto que les dije, hablarlo con los jugadores, hablarlo con mi familia, hablarlo con los directivos, comentar lo que yo sentía, tomar un
有一段时间，特别是因为现在是11月份，所以3月份我就没有离开过。
for a while, especially because it was November, I hadn't left in March.
un tiempo, sobre todo porque era noviembre, a marzo no había partido.
这是他个人的问题。
It was a personal matter of how he was.
Era una cuestión personal de cómo estaba.
完全，完全是身体上的。
Totally, totally physical.
Físico totalmente, totalmente.
还有教练组...
And the coaching staff...
Y el cuerpo técnico...
他是这么理解的。
That's how he understood it.
Así lo entendió.
而且，很明显我还没有达到百分百。
Besides, it was clear that I was not one hundred percent.
A parte se veía que yo no estaba al cien por cien.
我感觉到了，我不得不说出来。
and I felt it and I had to say it.
y lo sentía y lo tenía que decir.
因为？
Because?
¿Por qué?
因为也许
Because maybe
Porque a lo mejor
几个月后，他无法继续。
Months later he was not in a position to continue.
meses después no estaba en condiciones de seguir.
这是我们所在的地方，也是我所在的地方。
It's a place where we are, where I am.
Es un lugar donde estamos, donde estoy.
这需要是百分百的，因为他们需要它，球员也需要它。
that needs to be one hundred percent, because they require it, the players require it.
que necesita estar cien por cien, porque ellos lo requieren, los jugadores lo requieren.
因为选择需要它，因为它即将到来。
because the selection requires it and because it was something that was coming.
porque la selección lo requiere y porque se venía en cosa.
重要的美洲杯也随之而来。
The important Copa América was coming with that.
Venía la Copa América importante con que.
安赫尔即将退役，因为这可能是利奥的最后一届杯赛，因为我们是冠军，我们必须成为冠军
Ángel was retiring, because it could be Leo's last Cup, because we were champions and we had to be
Ángel se retiraba, con que podía ser la última Copa de Leo, con que éramos campeones y teníamos que estar
所以这是一个相当重的负担。
So it was quite a heavy load.
Entonces era una carga bastante fuerte.
我们必须全部对齐，教练是第一个，教练必须是第一个排队并成为
and we had to be all aligned, the coach was the first, the coach had to be the first to line up and be
y teníamos que estar todo alineado, el primero el entrenador, el entrenador tenía que ser el primero en alinearse y ser
与正在发生的事情一致，而且我身体不太好，我需要说出来，
consistent with what was happening and I was not well, I needed to say it,
consecuente con lo que estaba pasando y yo no estaba bien, lo necesitaba decir,
我认为在团队层面上它让我们更加团结。
And I think that on a group level it brought us together more.
Y creo que a nivel grupal a nosotros nos unió más.
在团队层面，我们更加团结，在球队层面，我从球员和教练组那里得到了很多关爱。
At the group level we unite more, at the team level I have had a lot of signs of affection from the players, from the coaching staff.
A nivel grupo nos unimos más, a nivel equipo he tenido un montón de muestras de cariño de los jugadores, de cuerpo técnico.
管理者、员工本身，对什么感兴趣
of the managers, of the people themselves, taking an interest in what
de los directivos, de la gente en sí, interesándose por lo que
因为发生的事情，我认为事后这是积极的。
because of what was happening and I think it was positive afterwards.
por lo que sucedía y yo creo que fue positivo después.
直到最后才赢得了杯赛......
The Cup was won until in the end...
Se ganó la Copa hacia que al final...
我最终变得非常优秀，但这确实需要变得优秀。
I ended up being very good, but it does require being good.
termino siendo muy bueno, pero sí que requiere estar bien.
我在笔记开头问过你关于2014年的事情
I asked you at the beginning of the note about that 2014
Te pregunté en el arranque de la nota por aquel 2014
如果你已经考虑成为一名教练，你就答应了。
And if you were already thinking about being a coach, you said yes.
Y si ya estabas pensando en ser entrenador, me dijiste que sí.
你能想象 10 年后 2034 年 9 月的生活吗？
Can you imagine life in September 2034, 10 years from now?
¿Te imaginas la vida en septiembre de 2034, dentro de 10 años?
不，不可能。
No, impossible.
No, imposible.
我无法想象，我无法想象在 2014 年或 2015 年……
I can't imagine it, I couldn't imagine in 2014 or 2015 that...
No me lo imagino, no me imaginaba en el 2014 o 2015 que...
我们会在这里，我无法想象......
that we were going to be here, I can't imagine...
que íbamos a estar acá, no me imagino...
超越我们正在玩的东西，因为我认为这是面对事情的方式
beyond what we are playing, because I think it is the way to face things and that
más allá de lo que estamos jugando, porque creo que es la manera de afrontar las cosas y que
发生在你身上的最好的事情就是不要考虑来世，因为。
The best thing that can happen to you is not to think about the afterlife because.
que lo mejor que te pueda pasar es no pensar en el más allá porque.
生活和足球有很多事情，今天你想到一件事，然后又发生另一件事。
Life and football have so many things that today you think one thing and then another happens.
La vida y el fútbol tienen tantas cosas que hoy pensar una cosa y después pasa otra.
我们会考虑接下来会发生什么，现在是预选赛，然后我们会看到结果。
We think about what's coming, that now are the qualifying matches and then we'll see.
Pensamos lo que viene, que ahora son los partidos eliminatoria y después ya se verá.
现在关闭 Pujato 和你的父母在你的生活中意味着什么？
What does it mean to close now yes Pujato and your parents in your life?
¿Qué significa para cerrar ahora sí Pujato y tus viejos en tu vida?
有时，
There are times when
Hay momentos en los que
你还认为我的父母会告诉我我做什么、说什么吗？
Do you still think what my parents are going to tell me about what I do, about what I say?
¿Pensás todavía qué me van a decir mis viejos frente a lo que hago, frente a lo que digo?
现在我不会感到兴奋，因为我已经很兴奋谈论它了。
Now I'm not going to get excited because I'm already very excited to talk about it.
Ahora no me voy a emocionar porque ya me emocione un montón hablar de ello.
这是我身上唯一的、最大的刺。
It is the only and great thorn in my side.
Es la única y la gran espina que tengo clavada.
当我们得到这一切时，我不知道是否...
When we got all this, I don't know if...
de cuando conseguimos todo esto, es que yo no sé si...
衡量我们通过他们的国家所取得的成就的大小，因为他们不是
take magnitude of what we have achieved by their state, because they are not
toman magnitud de lo que hemos conseguido por su estado, porque no están
正如人们所希望的那样，这就是我......
as one would like and that is what I...
como uno quisiera y es lo que a mí me...
赢得世界杯后的一整年，这都折磨着我，我说，好吧......
It tormented me that whole year after winning the World Cup, where I said, well...
Me atormentó todo ese año después de haber ganado el Mundial, donde yo digo, bueno...
因为他们将是世界上最幸福的人。
because they would be the happiest guys in the world.
porque serían los tipos más felices del mundo.
我家老头子是个男的...
My old man is a guy...
Mi viejo es un tipo...
他为我们、为我的兄弟、为我、为每个人而活。
who lived for and for us, for my brother, for me, for everyone.
que vivió por y para nosotros, para mi hermano, para mí, para todos.
他一生中所做的一切都是为了让我们能够成为……
And he has done everything he has done in his life so that we can become...
Y ha hecho todo lo que ha hecho en su vida para que nosotros podamos llegar a ser...
足球运动员并在一切事情上支持我们。
footballers and supported us in everything.
futbolistas y nos apoyó en todo.
我的老太太也一样，她到处跟着我爸爸，就像我妻子现在跟着我一样。
My old lady the same way, she followed my dad everywhere, like my wife now follows me.
Mi vieja igual, siguió a mi papá a todos lados, como ahora me sigue mi esposa a mí.
所以，这有点折磨我，并且永远困扰着我，让我知道他们是否
So, it was a bit what tormented me and will always haunt me to know if they
Entonces, era un poco lo que me atormentaba y siempre me va a perseguir saber si ellos
他们很享受我们所取得的成就。
They have enjoyed what we have achieved.
han disfrutado de lo que hemos conseguido.
因为对于我来说这是...
Because for me it is...
Porque para mí es...
这将是生活给我的最伟大的礼物。
It would be the greatest gift that life has given me.
sería el regalo más grande que me ha dado la vida.
我不知道我是否这么认为，有时你会表现出来，有时你不会，但是嘿，他们是......
I don't know if I think so, sometimes you show it, other times you don't, but hey, they are...
No sé si yo creo que sí, a veces lo demuestras, otras veces no, pero bueno, son...
这些都是生活中发生的事情，似乎有时当有人说话时他们总是说足球，足球......
These are things that happen in life and it seems that sometimes when someone talks they always say football, football...
Son cosas que pasan en la vida y parece que a veces cuando uno habla dice siempre fútbol, el fútbol...
还有其他更重要的事情，对我来说这四五年，是我职业生涯中最重要、最好的。
There are other more important things and for me these four or five years, right in the most important, the best of my career.
Hay otras cosas más importantes y a mí estos cuatro o cinco años, justo en los más importantes, a lo mejor de mi carrera.
足球或运动，我身上发生了一些事情......
football or sports, something has happened to me where...
fútbolística o deportiva, me ha pasado cosa en lo que...
这让我思考并说道，但还有比足球更重要的事情，尽管我们的国家
It has made me think and say, but there are more important things than football, even though our country
me ha hecho pensar y decir, pero hay cosas más importantes que en el fútbol, a pesar de que nuestro país
就像足球一样，如果我谈论足球，它就是一种宗教，但还有比足球更重要的事情。
Like football, if I talk about football it is a religion, but there are things more important than football.
Como fútbol, si hablo de fútbol es una religión, pero sí que hay cosas más importantes que el fútbol.
我认为家人为你感到骄傲，你的父母也为你感到骄傲。
I think the family is proud and your parents are also proud of you.
Yo creo que la familia está orgullosa y tus viejos también están orgullosos de vos.
嗯，我希望如此。
Well, I hope so.
Bueno, ojalá ojalá así sea.
砂矿。
Placer.
太感谢了。
Thank you so much.
Muchas gracias.
谢谢！
¡Gracias!